<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?workdir /C:\Drop3and4\Drop4\temp\pdf\oxygen_dita_temp?><?workdir-uri file:/C:/Drop3and4/Drop4/temp/pdf/oxygen_dita_temp/?><?path2project?><?path2project-uri ./?><concept-wr xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="psa1410807758201" xml:lang="en-us" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2" class="- topic/topic concept/concept concept-wr/concept-wr ">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1" class="- topic/title ">System Backups</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2" class="- topic/shortdesc ">HP Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade provides tools to back up <term ixia_locid="3" class="- topic/term ">system
      data</term> and <term ixia_locid="4" class="- topic/term ">Cinder volumes</term> so that they can be stored in
    external storage resources and used to restore a full cluster.</shortdesc>
 <prolog class="- topic/prolog ">
  <author ixia_locid="5" class="- topic/author ">Pedro Sanchez</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
  <p ixia_locid="6" class="- topic/p ">The backup and restore procedures can be summarized as follows:</p>
  <ul id="ul_at2_h3y_lp" class="- topic/ul ">
   <li ixia_locid="7" class="- topic/li ">
    <p ixia_locid="8" class="- topic/p ">Log in as user <nameliteral ixia_locid="9" class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b wr-sw-d/nameliteral ">wrsroot</nameliteral> to the
          console of the active controller.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="10" class="- topic/li ">
    <p ixia_locid="11" class="- topic/p ">Execute the backup procedures from the CLI. The backup files are stored in the directory
      <filepath ixia_locid="12" class="+ topic/ph sw-d/filepath ">/opt/backups</filepath> on the current controller node.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="13" class="- topic/li ">
    <p ixia_locid="14" class="- topic/p ">Copy the backup files to an external storage resource.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="15" class="- topic/li ">
    <p ixia_locid="16" class="- topic/p ">Shut down the cluster, and proceed with any maintenance operations that might
     be required. Ensure that all hosts are powered down.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="17" class="- topic/li ">
    <p ixia_locid="18" class="- topic/p ">Restore the cluster one host at a time. Start with the first controller, then
          the second controller, then storage nodes, and finally compute nodes.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
    <p ixia_locid="20" class="- topic/p ">It is important to note that a restore operation must be executed on the same
      cluster hardware where the backups were created, otherwise, the operation fails. Hardware
      differences affect the restore operation in multiple ways. For example, differences in
      Ethernet MAC addresses impact the networking metadata stored in the system data backup files.
      Also, storage devices with different sizes or geometries impact the metadata stored in the
      Cinder block storage database.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="19" class="- topic/p ">The backup and restore tools are designed to operate on an entire Titanium
   Server cluster. They are not suitable as a tool to back up and restore individual hosts.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>