<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="aet1461347433715" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Virtual Applications</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Titanium Server provides a flexible feature-rich cloud platform for
  hosting a wide variety of Virtual Applications ranging from Telecom to Industrial, Central Office
  to Customer Premise and much more.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="4">Titanium Server’s strength and flexibility in providing a Highly Available hosting environment
   allows it to host Virtual Applications in Telecom scenarios and Industrial scenarios that demand
   such high availability and robustness. A variety of HA application models can be hosted ranging
   from classic cloud protection pools to traditional Telco or Industrial 1:1 or 1:N Hot Standby
   Redundancy.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="5">Titanium Servers scalable and high performance Networking solution enables Telcos to include
   not only their Management and Control / Signaling Applications in their cloud-based solution, but
   also their high bandwidth Data Plane Applications as well. Titanium Server provides
   DPDK-accelerated L2 and L3 platform services and enables network-performance-optimized hosting of
   DPDK-based Telco Data Plane Applications. </p>
  <p ixia_locid="6">Titanium Server also provides an ideal hosting environment for Virtual Applications demanding
   high compute performance and/or high database capacity and performance, such as Home Subscriber
   Server (HSS) / Home Location Register (HLR) applications in Telco Central Offices. Titanium
   Server provides fine-tuned control over virtual CPU policies and scheduling as well as optimizes
   compute performance thru huge page memory performances. For storage capacity and performance,
   Titanium Server provides support for a highly scalable CEPH storage cluster with SSD-based
   journaling or SSD-based full cache tiering for economical storage performance at large scale. </p>
  <p ixia_locid="7">Titanium Server’s flexibility in deployment options ranges from hundreds of nodes down to just
   a single pair of servers. This allows Titanium Server to be deployed in central large-scale
   Telecom Data Centers or on customer premises in vCPE type solutions. </p>
  <p ixia_locid="8">Titanium Server can provide hosting for the complete range of Telecom Applications: Management
   Plane Applications, Control / Signaling Plane Applications and Data Plane Applications. This
   enables end-users of Titanium Server to deploy complete end-to-end Telco solutions on Titanium
   Server; examples of which include virtual Evolved Packet Core (vEPC), virtual IP Multimedia
   Subsystem (vIMS) and the new 5G networks. To accelerate the deployment of all these use cases,
   Telcos can leverage the extensive range of products from industry-leading partners that have been
   validated through Wind River’s Titanium Cloud ecosystem.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>