<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="axk1464968396598" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title ixia_locid="1">Preparing the region_config File</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">This file is required during Titanium Server region
        configuration.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
    </prolog>
    <taskbody>
        <context id="context_N1001F_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="4">
            <p ixia_locid="155">Installaton of Titanium Server as a Secondary Region uses a
                    <cmdname ixia_locid="156">config_region</cmdname> script which is analogous to the
                    <cmdname ixia_locid="157">config_controller</cmdname> script used for initial installation,
                except with extended functionality required for setting up services sharing with the
                Primary Region. </p>
            <p ixia_locid="158">The <cmdname ixia_locid="159">config_region</cmdname> script only
                supports file input for system configuration data; again, this is like the
                configuration file that is supported by the <cmdname ixia_locid="160">config_controller</cmdname> script.</p>
            <p ixia_locid="147">The region config file uses key-value pairs in standard INI format.
                It can be created manually or you can use the Titanium <filepath ixia_locid="25">config_gui</filepath> provided with the SDK to create it. The contents of the
                file are used as input to the <cmdname ixia_locid="26">config_region</cmdname>
                script, which is used to configure the first controller on the Titanium Server
                Secondary Region.</p>
            <p ixia_locid="148">A ‘write-enabled’ mode exists in the region configure file, called
                CREATE In [REGION_2_SERVICES]. When CREATE is set to Y, the expected endpoints,
                services tenant, services, and users will be created if they are not already present
                in the shared keystone. </p>
            <p ixia_locid="149">When CREATE is set to Y, password fields in the REGION_2_SERVICES
                section are optional; when not present a random password will be generated where
                necessary. </p>
            <p ixia_locid="150">Optional services Glance and Cinder are configured to be shared if
                they are under [SHARED_SERVICES], but not if they are under [REGION_2_SERVICES] (in
                which case they require password fields if CREATE is not Y). </p>
            <p ixia_locid="30">When CREATE is not present or is set to N, the primary region
                Keystone needs to be configured manually using OpenStack commands.</p>
            <p ixia_locid="152">For more information on the services that must be provisioned, see
                    <xref href="lbp1464960287653.xml" ixia_locid="154"/>.</p>
            <p ixia_locid="151">For more information on the <filepath ixia_locid="55">region_config</filepath> file, see <xref href="vqz1472582405090.xml" ixia_locid="146"/>.</p>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task-wr>