<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="bfh1466190844731" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Storage on Controller Hosts</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Controller hosts provide storage for the system database, and for system
  backup operations. </shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Edward Knowlton</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <section id="section_N10031_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="87">
   <p ixia_locid="89">On systems with controller storage, they also provide persistent storage for
    virtual machine images, using a secondary disk.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="90">Controller storage is configured initially at installation, using the
    controller configuration script. To utilize the maximum available space on the storage media,
    Wind River recommends that you use the default settings. You can change the allocations at any
    time after installation.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="389"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="390">US74975 created concept topic
     to support task topics for Horizon and CLI; added Ceph Mon Storage</draft-comment>Controller
    hosts provide the following types of storage:</p>
   <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="408">I'd consider changing the &lt;dd&gt;s below to full sentences with
    proper capitalization or perhaps use a table. Something seems odd about the fragments in the
    &lt;dd&gt;. (Just my opinion).</draft-comment>
   <dl>
    <dlentry ixia_locid="224">
     <dt ixia_locid="225">Database storage</dt>
     <dd ixia_locid="226">
      <p ixia_locid="108">the storage allotment for the OpenStack database</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry ixia_locid="227">
     <dt ixia_locid="228">Image storage</dt>
     <dd ixia_locid="229">
      <p ixia_locid="112">for a system that provides LVM-backed controller storage for VMs, the size
       of the partition to use for image storage</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry ixia_locid="230">
     <dt ixia_locid="231">Backup storage</dt>
     <dd ixia_locid="232">
      <p ixia_locid="116">the storage allotment for backup operations</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry ixia_locid="376">
     <dt ixia_locid="377">Volume storage</dt>
     <dd ixia_locid="378">
      <p ixia_locid="379"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="380">CGTS-3736 The GUI says
        "Cinder storage" but the config script says "Volume storage"</draft-comment>for a system
       that provides LVM-backed controller storage for VMs, the storage allotment for all Cinder
       volumes used by guest instances; also called <term ixia_locid="402">Cinder storage</term></p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry ixia_locid="391">
     <dt ixia_locid="392">Image Conversion Space</dt>
     <dd ixia_locid="393">
      <p ixia_locid="394"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="395">CGTS-3736
        added</draft-comment>the storage allotment for image caching and temporary image
       conversion</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry ixia_locid="396">
     <dt ixia_locid="397">Ceph Mon Storage</dt>
     <dd ixia_locid="398">
      <p ixia_locid="399"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="400">US74975
        added</draft-comment>for a system using Ceph storage, the storage allotment on the
       controller for Ceph monitoring</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
   </dl>
   <note id="note_N10096_N10022_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="210">
    <p ixia_locid="119">For clusters using a Ceph backend, volume storage and image storage are
     allotted on storage nodes, not on the controller node. To change the Cinder volume storage for
     a Ceph backend, <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="409">The next two xrefs are local in
      the system administration guide but not in the planning guide. Leaving as local formatting for
      now. – JM: Reversing decision due to unusable link in planning doc PDF. Changing to inter-book
      format.</draft-comment>see <ph ixia_locid="410" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="411">Titanium Server System
       Administration: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="412"><ph ixia_locid="413"><xref href="jow1414074138348.xml" ixia_locid="239"/></ph></cite>.</p>
   </note>
   <p ixia_locid="25">The storage allotments are configured initially during software installation.
    You can change them using the Web administration interface or the CLI. For more information, see
     <ph ixia_locid="414" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="415">Titanium Server System Administration:
       </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="416"><ph ixia_locid="417"><xref href="ers1464645579505.xml" ixia_locid="401"/></ph></cite>).</p>
   <p ixia_locid="247">To accommodate changes, there must be enough disk space on the controller,
    including headroom needed to complete the operation. The headroom required is 45 GiB on the
    primary disk for a cluster using controller storage with an LVM backend, or 65 GiB for a cluster
    using dedicated storage with a Ceph backend. This is in addition to the space required for any
    new allotments. The requested changes are checked against available space on the affected disks;
    if there is not enough, the changes are disallowed.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="403">To provide more space, you can replace the affected disk or disks. Database,
    image, and backup storage use space on the primary disk. Cinder volume storage (on a cluster
    with an LVM backend) uses space on a disk selected by device node number during controller
    configuration. The replacement disk must occupy the same device node number. Changes to the
    Cinder volume storage can also affect the primary disk because of the headroom requirement. </p>
   <p ixia_locid="404"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="405">US78833 / US77367 mention
     that ceph mon storage can use a secondary disk</draft-comment>Ceph monitor storage uses the
    primary disk by default. If a Ceph backend is added to an existing system, and there is
    insufficient space on the primary disk for the requested Ceph monitor storage, you can specify a
    secondary disk. Note that this requires a controller re-installation.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="304"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="346">US64033 removed caution that
     controller configurations must be identical</draft-comment>To pass the disk-space checks, any
    replacement disks must be installed before the allotments are changed.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N1010F_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="406">
   <title ixia_locid="407">Storage for System Use</title>
   <p ixia_locid="5">Internal database storage is provided using DRBD-synchronized partitions on the
    controller primary disks. The size of the database grows with the number of system resources
    created by the system administrator and the tenants. This includes objects of all kinds such as
    compute nodes, provider networks, images, flavors, tenant networks, subnets, virtual machine
    instances, and NICs. As a reference point, consider the following deployment scenario:</p>
   <ul id="ul_drv_fjf_4n">
    <li ixia_locid="6">
     <p ixia_locid="7">two controllers</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="8">
     <p ixia_locid="9">four compute nodes with dual Intel(R) Xeon(R) CPU E5-2670 v2 @ 2.50GHz
      each.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="10">
     <p ixia_locid="11">40 virtual machine instances</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="12">
     <p ixia_locid="13">120 tenant networks</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="14">
     <p ixia_locid="15">steady collection of power management statistics</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
   <p ixia_locid="16">The size of the database in this case is approximately 9 GB. With a suggested
    default of 20 GB, there is still plenty of room to grow. However, you should periodically
    monitor the size of the database to ensure that it does not become a bottleneck when delivering
    new services.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="48">For more information, see <cite ixia_locid="49">Titanium Server System
     Engineering Guidelines</cite>.</p>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>