<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="ccz1468530477955" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="163">PCI Passthrough Ethernet Interface Devices</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="164">For all purposes, a PCI passthrough interface behaves as if it were physically attached
  to the virtual machine.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="165">Your Name</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="6">Therefore, any potential throughput limitations coming from the virtualized
   environment, such as the ones introduced by internal copying of data buffers, are eliminated.
   However, by bypassing the virtualized environment, the use of PCI passthrough Ethernet devices
   introduces several restrictions that must be taken into consideration. They include:</p>
  <ul id="ul_mjs_m52_tp">
   <li ixia_locid="7">
    <p ixia_locid="8">no support for LAG, QoS, ACL, or host interface monitoring</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="9">
    <p ixia_locid="10">no support for live migration</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="11">
    <p ixia_locid="12">no access to the compute node's AVS switch</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="14">A passthrough interface bypasses the compute node's AVS switch completely, and
   is attached instead directly to the provider network's access switch. Therefore, proper routing
   of traffic to connect the passthrough interface to a particular tenant network depends entirely
   on the VLAN tagging options configured on both the passthrough interface and the access port on
   the switch.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="15">The access switch routes incoming traffic based on a VLAN ID, which ultimately
   determines the tenant network to which the traffic belongs. The VLAN ID is either explicit, as
   found in incoming tagged packets, or implicit, as defined by the access port's default VLAN ID
   when the incoming packets are untagged. In both cases the access switch must be configured to
   process the proper VLAN ID, which therefore has to be known in advance.</p>
  <draft-comment author="rstone" ixia_locid="158">CGTS-2187 adds; JO edited</draft-comment>
  <note id="note_N1006A_N1002C_N10029_N10001" ixia_locid="159" type="caution">
   <p ixia_locid="160">On cold migration, a PCI passthrough interface receives a new MAC address,
    and therefore a new <nameliteral ixia_locid="161">eth</nameliteral>x interface. The IP address
    is retained.</p>
  </note>
  <p ixia_locid="153"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="162">US64378 "interface" was
    "device"</draft-comment>To review the current PCI passthrough and SR-IOV interface assignments
   for a given provider network, see <ph ixia_locid="166" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="167">Titanium Server System Administration: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="168"><ph ixia_locid="169"><xref href="jow1439301559036.xml" ixia_locid="170"/></ph></cite>.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="16">In the following example a new virtual machine is launched by user <nameliteral ixia_locid="17">user1</nameliteral> on tenant <nameliteral ixia_locid="18">tenant1</nameliteral>, with a passthrough interface connected to the tenant network <nameliteral ixia_locid="19">net0</nameliteral> identified with VLAN ID 10.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>