<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="daz1474639350002" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Options for VM Customization</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">You can use flavors, flavor extra specifications, and image metadata to
  allocate host resources for a VM, and to fine-tune the use of host resources.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="14"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="5">new topic for
    restructuring</draft-comment>Administrators can define the basic resources available to VMs by
   creating and using <term ixia_locid="15">flavors</term>. Each flavor defines the virtual CPU,
   RAM, and disk resources to be allotted when a VM is launched. For more information, see <xref href="jow1404333663095.xml" ixia_locid="22"/></p>
  <p ixia_locid="16">To adjust how VMs use host resources such as NUMA nodes, physical interfaces,
   or selected PCI devices, administrators can add <term ixia_locid="17">extra specifications</term>
   to the flavors. For more information, see <xref href="jow1429538642910.xml" ixia_locid="23"/></p>
  <p ixia_locid="20">In many cases, administrators or tenants can use <term ixia_locid="19">image
    metadata</term> as an alternative to flavor extra specs. This can be useful where the added
   capability is required for only a few particular instances. For more information, see <xref href="smj1474984971094.xml" ixia_locid="24"/></p>
  <note id="note_N10053_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="25">
   <p ixia_locid="21">If an extra spec method and an image metadata method are both applied to the
    same instance, and the settings conflict, the method that is given priority depends on the
    specific capability. In cases where the flavor extra spec overrides the image metadata, an
    administator can use this to help manage tenant resource usage.</p>
  </note>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>