<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="gfc1464958432305" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Introduction to Regions</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">An OpenStack <term ixia_locid="15">region</term> is a discrete OpenStack system with its
  own set of resources and its own set of services. Typically, some services are shared with other
  OpenStack regions, notably the Keystone service. Other shared services may include Cinder and
  Glance.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="6">Regions can be categorized into two types:</p>
  <dl>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="7">
    <dt ixia_locid="8">Primary Region</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="9">
     <p ixia_locid="10">In a Primary Region, all OpenStack services used by the region run locally.
      This type of region typically provides shared services to other regions. </p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="11">
    <dt ixia_locid="12">Secondary Region</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="13">
     <p ixia_locid="14">In a Secondary Region, some OpenStack services used by the region run
      locally, while others run in another region. This type of region makes use of shared services,
      typically provided by the Primary Region.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
  <section id="section_N10058_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="16">
   <title ixia_locid="17">Supported Multi-Region Configurations</title>
   <draft-comment author="eknowlto" ixia_locid="18">US76710</draft-comment>
   <p ixia_locid="19">Titanium Server supports several configurations for regions.</p>
   <ul id="ul_pkx_w5w_tw">
    <li ixia_locid="20">
     <p ixia_locid="21">Titanium Server as Primary and Secondary Regions</p>
     <ul id="ul_es4_dlb_ww">
      <li ixia_locid="28">
       <p ixia_locid="29">provides a mechanism for scaling a Titanium Server Cloud beyond the limits
        of a single Titanium Server Cloud or Region</p>
      </li>
     </ul>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="24">
     <p ixia_locid="25">Third-Party OpenStack Cloud as Primary Region and Titanium Server as
      Secondary Region</p>
     <ul id="ul_zlf_llb_ww">
      <li ixia_locid="30">
       <p ixia_locid="31">provides a mechanism to extend an existing Third Party OpenStack Cloud
        with a Titanium Server Cloud, enabling users to incrementally add Titanium Server values
        such as High Availability and High Performance Networking to an existing cloud solution</p>
      </li>
     </ul>
    </li>
    <!--<li ixia_locid="22"><p ixia_locid="23">Titanium Server as the Primary Region and Third-Party OpenStack Cloud as Secondary Region</p><ul id="ul_oy5_jlb_ww"><li ixia_locid="32"><p ixia_locid="33">allows a Third Party OpenStack Cloud to leverage Shared Services from the Titanium Server Cloud</p></li></ul></li>-->
   </ul>
   <note id="note_N10088_N10058_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="26">
    <p ixia_locid="27">Titanium Server CPE configurations are not supported as Primary or Secondary
     Regions.</p>
   </note>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>