<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="hzf1461010518191" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="427">High-performance Networking</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="428">Titanium Server provides significantly improved network performance over the default
  open source OpenStack solution.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="429">Jim Owens</author>
    <author ixia_locid="430">Pedro Sanchez</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="26">At the center of Titanium Server Networking is a DPDK-Accelerated Virtual L2
      Switch (AVS), running on the compute node hosts. It provides connectivity between virtual
      machines on the same or different compute nodes, and between virtual machines and external
      networks. AVS supports a variety of network connectivity options with the hosted virtual
      machines: </p>
  <ul id="ul_mgc_xnp_nn">
      <li ixia_locid="27">
        <p ixia_locid="28">Unmodified guests can use Linux networking and virtio drivers. This
          provides a mechanism to bring existing applications into the production environment
          immediately.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="443"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="432">US79271
            added</draft-comment>For virtio interfaces, Titanium Server supports <nameliteral ixia_locid="434">vhost-user</nameliteral> transparently by default. This allows QEMU and
          AVS to share virtio queues through shared memory, resulting in improved performance over
          standard virtio.</p>
      </li>
   <li ixia_locid="29">
    <p ixia_locid="30">For backward compatibility, Accelerated Virtual Port (AVP-KMOD) drivers are
          also supported.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="31">
    <p ixia_locid="32">For the highest performance, guest applications can be modified to make use
          of Intel DPDK libraries and open-source AVP-PMD poll-mode drivers.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="253"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="396">US62989 mention
        DNAT</draft-comment>In addition to AVS, Titanium Server incorporates DPDK-Accelerated
      Neutron Virtual Router L3 Forwarding (AVR). Accelerated forwarding is used for directly
      attached tenant networks and subnets, as well as for gateway, SNAT, DNAT, and floating IP
      functionality.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="351">Titanium Server also supports direct guest access to NICs using PCI
      passthrough or SR-IOV, with enhanced NUMA scheduling options compared to standard
      OpenStack.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="412"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="405">US64378 added
    para</draft-comment>For further performance improvements, Titanium Server supports direct access
   to PCI-based hardware accelerators, such as the Coleto Creek encryption accelerator from Intel.
   Titanium Server manages the allocation of SR-IOV VFs to VMs, and provides intelligent scheduling
   to optimize NUMA node affinity.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="448">For more information, see <ph ixia_locid="449" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="450">Titanium Server
        Planning:</cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="451"><ph ixia_locid="452"><xref href="jow1423169316542.xml" ixia_locid="453"/></ph></cite></p>
    <section id="section_N10092_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="445">
      <title ixia_locid="446">High Performance Networking Drivers</title>
      <p ixia_locid="447">The Titanium Server SDK provides high-performance AVS-compatible
        networking drivers, including accelerated kernel network drivers and accelerated DPDK
        network drivers.</p>
    </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>