<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="ism1460999126189" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="356">Guest VLAN Support</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="357">Titanium Server guests can make use of Titanium Server-defined VLANs to encapsulate IP
  traffic from a single or multiple IP subnets on a virtual Ethernet interface.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="358">Jim Owens</author>
  <author ixia_locid="359">Ron Stone</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="250"> Titanium Server tenants can define one or more VLAN-tagged IP subnets on a
   single tenant network to allow their guests’ traffic to be encapsulated on VLAN IDs of their
   choice. These Titanium Server-defined VLAN-tagged IP subnets have access to all of the services
   of the virtualized network infrastructure, such as DHCP, virtual routing, meta-data server, and
   so on.</p>
  <draft-comment author="rstone" ixia_locid="354">US60634 adds</draft-comment>
  <p ixia_locid="353">Alternately, Titanium Server guests can make use of transparent VLANs, in
   which packets are encapsulated within a provider network segment without removing or modifying
   the guest VLAN tag(s). VLAN Transparent provides more flexibility with respect to how VLAN tagged
   packets are handled without requiring that you pre-define which VLAN instances will be used. A
   guest can send/receive VLAN tagged packets (802.1q) and/or double VLAN tagged packets (802.1ad)
   without first defining a VLAN-tagged subnet in Titanium Server. In addition, a VLAN transparent
   network will also propagate VLAN priority information (802.1p) to the destination VM instance.
   However, as a consequence of allowing arbitrary VLAN instances, you lose the ability to access
   DHCP servers, virtual routers, or meta-data servers over those VLAN-tagged networks. </p>
  <p ixia_locid="355">Support for Guest VLANs is a key capability that facilitates the porting of
   current user applications running on dedicated physical servers using VLANs to a virtualized
   environment.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>