<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="ixo1464634136835" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="89">Block Storage for Virtual Machines</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="90">Virtual machines use Titanium Server storage resources for root and
  ephemeral disks. </shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="91">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="81"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="71">US68057, US69978 updated
    section; US74975 updated for Ceph-backed remote ephemeral storage; US85034 add "Disk" to title
    to distinguish from new "Object Storage for Virtual Machines" topic</draft-comment>You can
   allocate root disk storage for virtual machines using the following:</p>
  <ul id="ul_d1c_j5k_s5">
   <li ixia_locid="82">
    <p ixia_locid="83">a Cinder volume</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="111">
    <p ixia_locid="112">ephemeral storage; one of</p>
    <ul id="ul_pgb_2j3_tw">
     <li ixia_locid="113">
      <p ixia_locid="93">ephemeral local storage on compute nodes, backed by LVM</p>
     </li>
     <li ixia_locid="114">
      <p ixia_locid="95">ephemeral local storage on compute nodes, backed by image file</p>
     </li>
     <li ixia_locid="115">
      <p ixia_locid="97">ephemeral remote storage on storage nodes, backed by Ceph</p>
     </li>
    </ul>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="88">The use of a Cinder volume or ephemeral storage is determined by the <uicontrol ixia_locid="72">Instance Boot Source</uicontrol> setting when an instance is launched. <option ixia_locid="109">Boot from volume</option> results in the use of a Cinder volume, while <option ixia_locid="110">Boot from image</option> results in the use of ephemeral storage</p>
  <p ixia_locid="664">Cinder-backed persistent storage for virtual machines is provided using either
   Ceph-backed OSD disks on high-availability storage hosts, or LVM-backed, DRBD-synchronized
   controller secondary disks on systems that do not use storage hosts.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="665"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="666">CGTS-4963 describe thin and
    thick provisioning alternatives</draft-comment>For a controller-based LVM Cinder backend, you
   can configure Titanium Server at installation to use thin or thick provisioning. Thin
   provisioning allocates space for the volume dynamically on the underlying physical disk. Thick
   provisioning creates a fixed-size volume. Thin provisioning offers support for fast secure
   deletion, but requires longer volume creation times. You can improve volume creation times by
   using SSDs for the underlying disks.</p>
  <note id="note_N102D4_N102A4_N10296_N1008F_N10063_N1005F_N10023_N10020_N10001" ixia_locid="662" type="caution">
   <p ixia_locid="663">The choice of thick or thin provisioning cannot be changed after
    installation. </p>
  </note>
  <p ixia_locid="98">Ephemeral storage for virtual machines, including swap disk storage, ephemeral
   disk storage, and root disk storage if the <uicontrol ixia_locid="73">Instance Boot
    Source</uicontrol> is set to <option ixia_locid="74">Boot from Image</option>, is by default
   provided locally on the compute nodes where the VMs are instantiated (local ephemeral storage).
   On Ceph systems, you can change this configuration to use storage node resources instead (remote
   ephemeral storage).</p>
  <p ixia_locid="99">On each individual compute host, you can configure the ephemeral storage to
   use:</p>
  <ul id="ul_oqs_lyj_dw">
   <li ixia_locid="100">
    <p ixia_locid="101">a local LVM-based backend, to optimize run-time I/O performance</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="102">
    <p ixia_locid="103">a CoW (Copy on Write) sparse-image-format backend, to optimize launch and delete
     performance</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="104">
    <p ixia_locid="105">a Ceph backend (on a system with storage nodes), to optimize migration capabilities</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="106">The ephemeral storage type is defined during installation, and can be modified
   using the Web administration interface or the CLI. <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="667">The following xref is local in the system admin guide but inter-book from the
    planning guide. Leaving with local formatting for now. – JM: Reversed decision due to unusable
    link in planning guide. Changed to inter-book format. Also updated the topic reference to point
    to the new revised topic (formerly, there were two topics with the same title, Jim resolved
    issue).</draft-comment>For more information, see <ph ixia_locid="668" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="669">Titanium Server System Administration: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="670"><ph ixia_locid="671"><xref href="jow1426181291481.xml" ixia_locid="672"/></ph></cite> .</p>
  <note conref="jow1426942555025.xml#jow1426942555025/note_local_storage_ephemeral" id="note_N10130_N1007C_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="62"/>
  <p ixia_locid="107">The choice of storage type affects migration behavior. For more information, see <xref href="ksh1464711502906.xml" ixia_locid="108"/>.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>