<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jhh1464706651355" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="210">Ceph Storage Pools</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="211">On a system that uses a Ceph storage backend, storage pools for images,
    volumes, ephemeral data, and object data are configured on the storage hosts.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="212">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
    <p ixia_locid="213"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="214">US74975 Added as a separate
        concept topic, to provide common information for the CLI and Horizon task topics. US84057
        updated for object pool</draft-comment>Titanium Server uses four pools:</p>
    <p ixia_locid="224"><ul id="ul_z5w_xwp_dw">
        <li ixia_locid="216">
          <p ixia_locid="217">Cinder Volume Storage pool</p>
        </li>
        <li ixia_locid="218">
          <p ixia_locid="219">Glance Image Storage pool</p>
        </li>
        <li ixia_locid="226">
          <p ixia_locid="227">Nova Ephemeral Disk Storage pool</p>
        </li>
        <li ixia_locid="228">
          <p ixia_locid="229">Swift Object Storage pool</p>
        </li>
      </ul>These pools share the available Ceph storage provided by the storage host resources.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="225">Initial quotas for each pool are defined during system installation. Within
      the bounds of these quotas, storage for each of the pools is allocated dynamically as
      required. To optimize resource usage, you can adjust the quota on each pool. The sum of the
      quotas must equal the total available space in gibibytes (GiB).</p>
    <p ixia_locid="174"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="209">US74975 changed "Glance
        Image Pool" to "pool" throughout, and reworded. REWORDING NEEDS REVIEW</draft-comment>If you
      set a quota to <nameliteral ixia_locid="175">0</nameliteral>, the quota is deactivated. The
      pool size is not restricted, and can grow to fill the entire available storage space.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="177">If you set the quota to less than its current size, new space allocation
      requests are served only after the pool size drops below the new ceiling. </p>
    <p ixia_locid="178">If you set quotas so that the total value exceeds the available Ceph
      storage, restrictions on all allocation requests are removed.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="222">To view and change the size of the storage pools, see <xref href="gut1462475554017.xml" ixia_locid="223"/>.</p>
  <note id="note_N10032_N10021_N1001E_N10001" ixia_locid="198">
   <p ixia_locid="195"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="196">US77470 mention adding
          storage hosts</draft-comment>To increase the available storage, you can also add storage
        hosts, up to a maximum of four pairs. For instructions, see <ph ixia_locid="182" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="183">Titanium Server Installation for Ceph-backed
            Systems:</cite>
        </ph><cite ixia_locid="184"><ph ixia_locid="185"><xref href="uid1473354209921.xml" ixia_locid="230">Installing Software on Controller-1 or a Compute or Storage
        Host</xref></ph></cite>.</p>
  </note>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>