<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1443018695917" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="25">Methods for Adding and Configuring Hosts</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Titanium Server supports more than one way of adding and configuring
  hosts.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="26">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="6">US62814 new topic</draft-comment>
  <p ixia_locid="65" product="tis_cpe">After initializing and configuring an active controller, you
   can add and configure a backup controller as follows:</p>
  <p ixia_locid="66" product="tis_std">After initializing and configuring an active controller, you
   can add and configure a backup controller and additional compute or storage hosts as follows:</p>
  <ul id="ul_xvc_fmk_lt">
   <li ixia_locid="27">
    <p ixia_locid="28">Using the web administration interface (Horizon).</p>
    <p ixia_locid="29">With this method, you power on a new host, causing it to be auto-discovered
     and added to the system inventory, and then you use the Host Inventory in the web
     administration interface to assign a personality. For detailed instructions, see <xref href="uid1473354209921.xml" ixia_locid="61"/>.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="42">
    <p ixia_locid="43">Using the <cmdname ixia_locid="16">system host-update</cmdname> command.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="18">With this method, you power on a new host, causing it to be auto-discovered
     and added to the system inventory, and then you use <cmdname ixia_locid="44">system
      host-update</cmdname> to assign a personality. For detailed instructions, see <xref href="lpu1473354591768.xml" ixia_locid="62"/>.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="39">
    <p ixia_locid="40">Using the <cmdname ixia_locid="11">system host-add</cmdname> command.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="13">With this method, you add one or more host entries to the system inventory,
     assigning a personality, MAC address, IP address, and so on for each host, and then you power
     on the hosts, causing them to to be recognized and configured according to the system inventory
      entry.<ph ixia_locid="67" product="tis_std"> For more information, see <xref href="jow1442870328643.xml" ixia_locid="63"/>.</ph></p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="54" product="tis_std">
    <p ixia_locid="55">Using the <cmdname ixia_locid="56">system host-bulk-add</cmdname> command</p>
    <p ixia_locid="23">With this method, you define multiple hosts in an XML manifest, specifying
     personality, MAC address, IP address, and so on for each host, and then you use use <cmdname ixia_locid="57">system host-bulk-add</cmdname> to add them to the system inventory and
     optionally power them on. For more information, see <xref href="jow1441308518576.xml" ixia_locid="64"/>.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="58" product="tis_std">After adding a compute host or storage host, you can apply
    <term ixia_locid="59">hardware profiles</term> to complete the host configuration. For more
   information, see <xref href="jow1404333787693.xml" ixia_locid="60"/>.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>