<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1423173019489" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Shared (VLAN) Ethernet Interfaces</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The management, OAM, infrastructure, and data networks can share Ethernet
    or aggregated Ethernet interfaces using VLAN tagging.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
    <p ixia_locid="4"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="73">US82332 updated for new interface
        names</draft-comment>The OAM, infrastructure, and data networks can use VLAN tagging,
      allowing them to share an Ethernet or aggregated Ethernet interface with other networks. The
      internal management network can also be implemented as a VLAN-tagged network on the interface
      used for PXE booting.</p>
    <note id="note_N1002C_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="70">
      <p ixia_locid="71">You cannot configure a data VLAN or add a data network on an aggregated
        Ethernet interface.</p>
    </note>
    <p ixia_locid="6">For a system using all four networks, the following arrangements are
      possible:</p>
    <ul id="ul_y5k_zg2_zq">
      <li ixia_locid="7">
        <p ixia_locid="8">One interface for the internal management network, another interface for
          the OAM network, a third for the infrastructure network, and one or more additional
          interfaces for data networks.</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="9">
        <p ixia_locid="10">One interface for the internal management network, and a second interface
          for either the OAM or infrastructure network, with the remaining networks implemented
          using VLAN tagging on either interface.</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="11">
        <p ixia_locid="12">One interface for the internal management network, and a second carrying
          the OAM and infrastructure networks, both implemented using VLAN tagging, with data
          networks implemented on either or both interfaces using VLAN tagging.</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="13">
        <p ixia_locid="14">One interface for the internal management network, with the OAM,
          infrastructure, and data networks also implemented on it using VLAN tagging.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    <note id="note_N100E6_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="66">
      <p ixia_locid="67"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="88">CGTS-5862
          corrections</draft-comment>Data networks implemented using VLAN tagging are not compatible
        with VLAN-based provider networks. (Stacked VLANs are not supported.) To use a VLAN provider
        network on a shared ethernet interface, you can edit a management or infrastructure
        interface to attach also to a data network, and then select the VLAN provider network for
        the consolidated interface. For more information, see the network type discussion in <ph ixia_locid="77" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="78">Titanium Server System
            Administration: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="79"><ph ixia_locid="80"><xref href="jow1426955886080.xml" ixia_locid="81"/></ph></cite>. </p>
    </note>
    <p ixia_locid="68">Options to share an interface using VLAN tagging are presented during the
      configuration controller script. To attach an interface to other networks after configuration,
      you can edit the interface.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="82">For more information about configuring VLAN interfaces, see <ph ixia_locid="83" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="84">Titanium Server System Administration:
        </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="85"><ph ixia_locid="86"><xref href="jow1426951757970.xml" ixia_locid="87"/></ph></cite>
    </p>
  </conbody>
</concept-wr>