<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333736797" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">Internal Management Network Planning</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The internal management network is a private network, visible only to
        the hosts in the cluster.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="12">Jim Owens</author>
        <author ixia_locid="3">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="4">You must consider the following guidelines:</p>
        <ul id="ul_gqd_gj2_4n">
            <li ixia_locid="13">
                <p ixia_locid="14">By default, the internal management network is used for PXE
                    booting of new hosts, and therefore must be untagged. It is also limited to
                    IPv4, because the Titanium Server installer does not support IPv6 UEFI booting.
                    If, for deployment reasons, the internal management network needs to be on a
                    VLAN-tagged network, or if it must support IPv6, you can configure the optional
                    untagged PXE boot network for PXE booting of new hosts using IPv4.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="28">
                <p ixia_locid="29">The internal management network and the infrastructure network
                    must use the same IP version (IPv4 or IPv6).</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="7">
                <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="614">In the next sentence, should this be
                    "Gb"?</draft-comment>
                <p ixia_locid="8">You can use any 1 G or 10 G interface on the hosts to connect to
                    this network, provided that the interface supports network booting and can be
                    configured from the BIOS as the primary boot device.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="613">
                <p ixia_locid="24">The infrastructure network is automatically assigned the same
                    type of IP address assignment as the internal management network (dynamic or
                    static).</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="18">
                <p ixia_locid="19">If static IP address assignment is used, you must use the
                        <cmdname ixia_locid="21">system host-add</cmdname> command to add new hosts,
                    and to assign IP addresses manually. New hosts are <i ixia_locid="610">not</i>
                    automatically added to the inventory when they are powered on, and they display
                    the following message on the host
                    console:<codeblock ixia_locid="611"><systemoutput ixia_locid="612">This system has been configured with static management
and infrastructure IP address allocation. This requires
that the node be manually provisioned in System
Inventory using the 'system host-add' CLI, GUI, or
sysinv-api equivalent.</systemoutput></codeblock>
                </p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="9">
                <p ixia_locid="10">For the IPv4 address plan, use a private IPv4 subnet as specified
                    in RFC 1918. This  helps prevent unwanted cross-network traffic on this
                    network.</p>
                <p ixia_locid="11">It is suggested that you use the default subnet and addresses provided by the controller
     configuration script.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="25">
                <p ixia_locid="26">You can assign a range of addresses on the management subnet for
                    use by Titanium Server. If you do not assign a range, Titanium Server takes
                    ownership of all available addresses.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="15">
                <p conref="jow1419267499106.xml#jow1419267499106/multicast_in_use" ixia_locid="16"/>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="615">
                <p ixia_locid="616"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="617">CGTS-5681 added</draft-comment>For multi-region
                    deployments, you can define a restricted multicast addressing range on the
                    management network during system installation. Addresses for affected services
                    are allocated automatically from the range.  The same range also applies to the
                    infrastructure network.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>