<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333737981" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">OAM Network Planning</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The OAM (operations, administration, and management) network enables
        the Web administration interface, the command-line management clients, SNMP interface, and
        the REST APIs to manage the Titanium Server cluster.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="18">Jim Owens</author>
        <author ixia_locid="3">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="389">The OAM Network is also used for OpenFlow and OVSDB connectivity to an SDN Controller in
            Titanium Server SDN Configurations, and for syslog connectivity to a Remote Log Server
            if Titanium Server remote logging is configured. </p>
        <p ixia_locid="19">On systems where an optional board management network is configured for external access,
            the OAM network also provides access to the board management modules.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="4"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="377">US62821 state that IPv6 is
                supported.</draft-comment>The OAM network supports IPv4 or IPv6 addressing. Consider
            the following guidelines:</p>
        <ul id="ul_uj3_yk2_4n">
            <li ixia_locid="5">
                <p ixia_locid="373">Deploy proper firewall mechanisms to access this network. Ensuring
                    that access to the Titanium Server management interfaces is not compromised
                    should be of primary concern.</p>
                <p ixia_locid="374"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="375">US65292 added
                        para about default firewall and optional rules file:</draft-comment>Titanium
                    Server includes a default firewall for the OAM network, using the <nameliteral ixia_locid="376">Netfilter</nameliteral> framework. You can optionally
                    configure the system to support additional rules. For more information, see
                        <xref href="jow1443627833422.xml" ixia_locid="390"/>.</p>
                <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="391">The Firewall Options topic referenced above is also
                    included in the System Administration guide. May want to consider removing that
                    topic from this guide as it seems to be detailed information so perhaps not
                    needed in this planning guide. If topic is removed from this guide, the xref
                    here needs to change to include a &lt;cite&gt; for the Titanium Server System
                    Administration doc.</draft-comment>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="7">
                <p ixia_locid="8">Consider whether the OAM network needs access to the open
                    Internet. Limiting access to an internal network might be advisable, keeping in
                    mind that access to configured DNS and NTP servers may still be needed.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="9">
                <p ixia_locid="10">VLAN tagging is supported, enabling this network to share an
                    interface with the internal management or infrastructure networks.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="378">
                <p ixia_locid="379"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="380">US62821 bullet
                        added</draft-comment>The IP addresses of the DNS and NTP servers must match
                    the IP address plan (IPv4 or IPv6) of the OAM network.</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="11">
                <p ixia_locid="12">For an IPv4 address plan:</p>
                <ul id="ul_ipp_qs2_4n">
                    <li ixia_locid="13">
                        <p ixia_locid="14">The OAM floating IP address is the only address that
                            needs to be visible externally. Therefore you must plan for valid
                            definitions of its IPv4 subnet and default gateway.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li ixia_locid="15">
                        <p ixia_locid="16">The physical IPv4 addresses for the controllers don't
                            need to be visible externally, unless you plan to use them during SSH
                            sessions to prevent potential service breaks during the connection. You
                            still need to plan for their IPv4 subnet, but you can limit access to
                            them as required.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li ixia_locid="381">
                        <p ixia_locid="382"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="383">US62821
                                bullet added</draft-comment>Outgoing packets from the active or
                            secondary controller use the controller's IPv4 physical address, not the
                            OAM floating IP address, as the source address. </p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="384">
                <p ixia_locid="385"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="386">US62821 bullet
                        and sub-bullet added</draft-comment>For an IPv6 address plan:</p>
                <ul id="ul_gqn_s1m_vt">
                    <li ixia_locid="387">
                        <p ixia_locid="388">Outgoing packets from the active controller use the OAM
                            floating IP address as the source address. Outgoing packets from the
                            secondary controller use the secondary controller's IPv6 physical IP
                            address.</p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="20">
                <p conref="jow1419267499106.xml#jow1419267499106/multicast_in_use" ixia_locid="21"/>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="392">
                <p ixia_locid="393"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="394">CGTS-5681 added</draft-comment>For multi-region
                    deployments, you can define a restricted multicast addressing range on the OAM
                    network during system installation.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>