<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1453573276553" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Keystone Account Authentication</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">OpenStack tenants and users are authenticated by the OpenStack Keystone identity
  service.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="4"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="5">US71877 new
   topic</draft-comment>For tenant and user authentication, OpenStack supports a mixed backend that
   can use both SQL for local Keystone accounts and LDAP for centrally managed Keystone accounts. By
   default, Titanium Server uses the SQL identity service, and maintains the SQL database on the
   controller. For centrally managed acccounts, you can add an LDAP identity service for Keystone
   user accounts, and use a remote LDAP server backend. To add the LDAP identity service, see <xref href="qcj1465221711259.xml" ixia_locid="68"/>.</p>
  <note id="note_N10027_N10022_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="62" type="caution">
   <p ixia_locid="63">To ensure that all OpenStack users are managed by the LDAP identity service,
    you must configure the service <i ixia_locid="64">before</i> creating the OpenStack users.</p>
  </note>
  <p ixia_locid="7">Titanium Server implements Keystone LDAP authentication using the Keystone API
   v2, preserving compatibility with earlier OpenStack releases. The implementation provides for
   LDAP user account management, while maintaining the SQL backend for service accounts to simplify
   the configuration process. All authentication requests are handled first by the SQL service. If
   no entry is found, they are referred to the LDAP service.</p>
  <note id="note_N10049_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="69">
   <p ixia_locid="66"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="67">CGTS-5153 / US89717 add
     note</draft-comment>By default, a Keystone token expires after one hour. You can increase the
    expiration time if required. For more information, see <xref href="rtt1479843799021.xml" ixia_locid="70"/>.</p>
  </note>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>