<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1426948577755" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Network Interface Provisioning</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Before you can unlock and use the compute or storage nodes, you must
  configure the interfaces to attach them to networks.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="6">Some interfaces require manual provisioning before the nodes can be
   unlocked.</p>
  <ul id="ul_ecp_4fk_lr">
   <li ixia_locid="41">
    <p ixia_locid="42"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="43">US64033 added</draft-comment>For the second controller node,
     you must attach an interface to the OAM network, and to the infrastructure network if used,
     before you can unlock the node.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="10">
    <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="37">US62814 added clause for compute node infra IP
     static assignment to the compute nodes. (2015-10-26 A previous change under this comment,
     indicating that you don't need to attach infra interfaces for the storage nodes, and that you
     must assign them IP addresses if static addressing is in use, was incorrect and has been
     removed.)</draft-comment>
    <p ixia_locid="11">For a storage node, you must attach an interface to the infrastructure
     network before you can unlock the node.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="12">
    <p ixia_locid="29">For a compute node, you must attach interfaces to provider networks before
          you can unlock the node. The provider networks must be set up beforehand; <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="193">This topic ("Network Interface Provisioning") appears
            in the system admin guide and the installation guides. Updated the interbook reference
            to point to system admin guide (was incorrectly pointing to cloud admin guide). However,
            this is a local reference in the sys admin guide and interbook in the installation
            guide. (JO For the Install Guide, a better reference would be  "Configuring Provider
            Networks at Installation," which is in the Install Guide but not the Sys Admin. This is
            another case where using relationship tables would help.)</draft-comment>for more
          information, see <ph ixia_locid="188" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="189">Titanium Server System Administration:</cite>
          </ph><cite ixia_locid="190"><ph ixia_locid="191"><xref href="jow1404333519516.xml" ixia_locid="14"/></ph></cite> . </p>
    <!-- p ixia_locid="29">For a compute node, you must attach interfaces to provider networks before
     you can unlock the node. The provider networks must be set up beforehand; for more information,
     see <cite ixia_locid="189">Titanium Server Cloud Administration: Configuring Provider
      Networks</cite>. </p -->
    <p ixia_locid="30">If the compute cluster uses an infrastructure network, you must attach an
     interface to the infrastructure network before you can unlock the node. In addition, if the
     infrastructure uses static addressing, you must assign an IP address to the interface using the
      <cmdname ixia_locid="40">system host-addr-add</cmdname> command.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="145">Titanium Server supports three types of interfaces:<dl>
    <dlentry ixia_locid="146">
     <dt ixia_locid="147">Ethernet interfaces</dt>
     <dd ixia_locid="148">
      <p ixia_locid="149">These are created automatically for each port on the host. You must
       configure Ethernet interfaces by specifying the network type. </p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry ixia_locid="151">
     <dt ixia_locid="152">aggregated Ethernet interfaces</dt>
     <dd ixia_locid="153">
      <p ixia_locid="154">For link protection, you can create an aggregated Ethernet interface with
       two or more ports, and configure it with the network type.</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
    <dlentry ixia_locid="156">
     <dt ixia_locid="157">VLAN interfaces</dt>
     <dd ixia_locid="158">
      <p ixia_locid="159">To support multiple interfaces on the same physical Ethernet or aggregated
       Ethernet interface, you can create VLAN interfaces and configure them with the network
       type.</p>
     </dd>
    </dlentry>
   </dl></p>
  <p ixia_locid="15">The procedure for attaching an interface depends on the interface type.</p>
    <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="194">The xrefs in the &lt;ul&gt; appear in the sys admin guide and the
      install guide so are always local for this topic.</draft-comment>
  <ul id="ul_pcn_f5q_lr">
   <li ixia_locid="16">
    <p ixia_locid="17">To attach an Ethernet interface, see <xref href="jow1426949897008.xml" ixia_locid="18"/>.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="19">
    <p ixia_locid="20">To attach an aggregated Ethernet interface, see <xref href="jow1426951671346.xml" ixia_locid="21"/>.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="22">
    <p ixia_locid="23">To attach a VLAN interface, see <xref href="jow1426951757970.xml" ixia_locid="24"/>.</p>
    <note id="note_N1007F_N10071_N1004F_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="34">
     <p ixia_locid="35">To attach a data network to an existing management or infrastructure network
      interface<!-- using a method that supports VLAN provider networks-->, see <xref href="jow1414000462559.xml" ixia_locid="36"/>.</p>
    </note>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="25">As an alternative, you can use the CLI to attach interfaces. See <xref href="jow1427029415968.xml" ixia_locid="26"/>.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="128">Logical interfaces of network types <nameliteral ixia_locid="129">oam</nameliteral> and <nameliteral ixia_locid="130">mgmt</nameliteral> cannot be deleted. They
   can only be modified to use different physical ports when required. </p>
  <p ixia_locid="27">For more information on interfaces, see <ph ixia_locid="195" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="192">Titanium Server Planning: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="196"><ph ixia_locid="197"><xref href="jow1404333731990.xml" ixia_locid="198"/></ph></cite>.</p>
  <note id="note_N10095_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="31">
   <p ixia_locid="32"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="44">US64033 remove mention of infra
          and OAM being fixed on "controllers"</draft-comment>On compute and storage nodes, the
        Ethernet interface for the internal management network is attached automatically, to support
        installation using PXE booting. On controller nodes, the interface for the internal
        management network is attached according to the settings specified during the controller
        configuration script. <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="199">This topic ("Network
          Interface Provisioning") appears in the system admin guide and the installation guides.
          Updated the interbook reference to point to system installation guide. However, this is a
          local reference in the installation guide and interbook in the system admin guide. (JO I
          don't understand this comment, maybe misplaced?)</draft-comment>For more information, see
          <ph ixia_locid="200" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="201">Titanium Server
            Installation: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="202"><ph ixia_locid="203"><xref href="ekn1460145735111.xml" ixia_locid="5"/></ph></cite>.</p>
  </note>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>