<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1409240700100" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Customizing Images with User Data In a Heat Template</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">You can provide bootstrap configuration for an instance at launch by
    including user data in a Heat template.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="4">You can include user data by defining a <nameliteral ixia_locid="5">UserData</nameliteral> property for an instance. This sends configuration instructions to
      the instance at launch. For an example of user data, see the <filepath ixia_locid="6">CombinationAutoScaling.yaml</filepath> template included with Titanium Server.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="7">Normally, this requires <libraryname ixia_locid="8">cloud-init</libraryname> to
      be installed in the guest, because the user data is converted to MIME format and then
      interpreted by <libraryname ixia_locid="9">cloud-init</libraryname>. For instances that do not
      include <libraryname ixia_locid="10">cloud-init</libraryname>, you can bypass the MIME
      conversion of user data by invoking a Wind River extension property and assigning the value
        <nameliteral ixia_locid="14">'RAW'</nameliteral>. This allows the VM to retrieve the
      specified user data in unaltered format through a simple REST API call to the metadata server.
      The name of the property follows the convention for the associated resource type. For an AWS
      resource (for example, <nameliteral ixia_locid="15">AWS::EC2::Instance</nameliteral>), use
        <parmname ixia_locid="11">UserDataType</parmname>. For an OpenStack resource (for example,
        <nameliteral ixia_locid="16">OS::Nova::Server</nameliteral>), use <parmname ixia_locid="17">user_data_format</parmname>. The following code fragment shows the property used with an
      OpenStack resource.</p>
  <codeblock ixia_locid="13">...
Srv:
   type: OS::Nova::Server
    properties:
      name: l3-forwarding
      …
      user_data_format: 'RAW'
      user_data:
        Fn::Base64:
            Fn::Replace:
            - 'OS::stack_name': {Ref: 'OS::stack_name'}
            - |
              #cloud-config

              runcmd:
               - ifconfig eth1 1.1.1.1/24 up
               - ifconfig eth2 2.2.2.1/24 up
               - echo 1 &gt; /proc/sys/net/ipv4/ip_forward
               - sed -i -e 's#.*\(net.ipv4.ip_forward\).*#\1 = 1#g' /etc/sysctl.conf
               - ip route add 192.50.0.0/16 via 1.1.1.10
               - ip route add 192.51.0.0/16 via 2.2.2.10
...</codeblock>
    <note id="note_N10063_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="18">
      <p ixia_locid="19">For a VM to access user data, it must have a DHCP-enabled interface on a
        tenant network that has a Neutron router. Typically, this is the interface to the VM's OAM
        network or an internal network. The Neutron router provides a route to the metadata server,
        which provides instances with access to user data.</p>
    </note>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>