<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333645456" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <!-- Modification History
   -->
    <title ixia_locid="1">Resource Usage</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Usage of system resources is monitored by Ceilometer, the standard
        OpenStack mechanism for collecting and distributing performance monitoring samples from the
        cluster. The Titanium Server cluster extends Ceilometer with improved reports and new tools
        to facilitate offline analysis of the collected data.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="249">Jim Owens</author>
        <author ixia_locid="3">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="4">Performance Monitor (PM) samples are periodically collected from different
            resources such as hosts, virtual machine instances, AVS, and others. They include CPU
            and memory utilization, network traffic counters, storage space, and several more. By
            default the samples are stored in a database which is used for reporting activities such
            as:</p>
        <ul id="ul_pfp_vlr_j4">
            <li ixia_locid="5">
                <p ixia_locid="6">command line queries and graphical charts</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="7">
                <p ixia_locid="8">triggering of threshold alarms</p>
            </li>
            <li ixia_locid="9">
                <p ixia_locid="10">triggering of threshold actions. The most common example is Heat actions to scale up and
          down a resource.</p>
            </li>
        </ul>
        <p ixia_locid="11">The Ceilometer database is periodically cleaned in order to contain its size and prevent the
      overuse of storage resources on the controller nodes.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="12">The Ceilometer implementation in Titanium Server improves on several
            aspects. They are described in the following sections.</p>
        <section id="section_N10048_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="13">
            <title ixia_locid="14">Optimized Ceilometer Filters</title>
            <p ixia_locid="15">The Ceilometer implementation in Titanium Server is specially tuned
                to allow time-sensitive actions, such as Heat autoscaling, to take place in response
                to relatively high-frequency sample rates of system events. The size of both the
                Ceilometer database and the CSV files are maintained under control at all times,
                while still enabling the required system actions to take place in real-time.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>