<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr domains="(topic concept concept-wr)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic wr-sw-d)                            (topic xml-d)   " id="jow1404333737339" xml:lang="en-us" xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/">
    <title ixia_locid="1">Infrastructure Network Planning</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The infrastructure network is a private network visible only to the
        hosts in the cluster. It is optional unless storage nodes are part of the
        cluster.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="25">Jim Owens</author>
        <author ixia_locid="3">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <p ixia_locid="26"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="27">US62814
                updated</draft-comment>For the most part, the infrastructure network shares the
            design considerations applicable to the internal management network. It can be
            implemented using a 10 Gb Ethernet interface. It can be VLAN-tagged, enabling it to
            share an interface with the management or OAM network. It can own the entire IP address
            range on the subnet, or a specified range.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="33">You can add an infrastructure network after system installation. For more
            information, see <ph ixia_locid="18" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="19">Titanium Server System Administration: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="20"><ph ixia_locid="21"><xref href="jow1420473404578.xml" ixia_locid="34"/></ph></cite>.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="28">The infrastructure network supports dynamic or static IP address
            assignment. The setting is determined by the setting for the internal management
            network. If static assignment is used, you must manually assign IP addresses on the
            infrastructure network for the other hosts in the cluster, using the <cmdname ixia_locid="29">system host-addr-add</cmdname> command.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="37"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="38">CGTS-5681 added</draft-comment>If a multicast messaging
            range is assigned on the management network, the infrastructure network uses the same
            range.</p>
        <p ixia_locid="31"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="32">US61937 / US65963 added:</draft-comment>The infrastructure
            network must use the same IP version as the management network (IPv4 or IPv6).</p>
        <p ixia_locid="5">The decision whether to implement an infrastructure network depends on the
            infrastructure traffic levels expected. The following table provides general guidelines
            on when to implement the infrastructure network, using the number of compute nodes in
            the Titanium Server cluster as an indication of expected traffic levels.</p>
        <simpletable id="simpletable_lgh_vms_14" relcolwidth="1.0* 3.0*">
            <sthead>
                <stentry ixia_locid="6">
                    <p ixia_locid="7">Number of Compute Nodes</p>
                </stentry>
                <stentry ixia_locid="8">
                    <p ixia_locid="9">Infrastructure Network Implementation</p>
                </stentry>
            </sthead>
            <strow>
                <stentry ixia_locid="10">
                    <p ixia_locid="11">2 to 4</p>
                </stentry>
                <stentry ixia_locid="12">
                    <p ixia_locid="13">No infrastructure network required. All infrastructure
                        traffic is carried over the internal management network.</p>
                </stentry>
            </strow>
            <strow>
                <stentry ixia_locid="14">
                    <p ixia_locid="15">5 or more</p>
                </stentry>
                <stentry ixia_locid="35">
                    <p ixia_locid="36">Use 10 Gb Ethernet</p>
                </stentry>
            </strow>
        </simpletable>
        <p ixia_locid="22">In addition to the number of compute nodes, other factors must be taken into account when
            deciding the type of infrastructure network to use. For example, live migration of
            large, memory-intensive, guest applications is likely to require additional network
            resources that might not be available in the current configuration. It is always safe to
            implement the fastest infrastructure network possible.</p>
        <note id="note_N10095_N1001D_N10001" ixia_locid="23">
            <p conref="jow1419267499106.xml#jow1419267499106/multicast_in_use" ixia_locid="24"/>
        </note>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>