<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept-wr id="jow1404333831397" xml:lang="en-us">
    <!-- Modification History

 -->
    <title ixia_locid="1">Usage Caveats</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">There are some usage issues you should be aware of when working with this
  release.</shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
        <author ixia_locid="4">Pedro Sanchez</author>
    </prolog>
    <conbody>
        <section id="section_N10027_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="54">
            <title ixia_locid="55">15.12 ini files are not forward compatible with 16.10</title>
            <p ixia_locid="56">Files must be updated to include two new mandatory keys:
                MULTICAST_CIDR for MGMT_NETWORK &amp; OAM_NETWORK. The VERSION field must be updated
                to 16.10. </p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10034_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="57">
            <title ixia_locid="58">For HP ProLiant GEN 9 Servers</title>
            <p ixia_locid="59">For HP ProLiant GEN 9 servers, turn off RMRR requests in the BIOS
                before installing or upgrading to this software release. Contact the hardware vendor
                for more details on the upgrade procedure. </p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10041_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="60">
            <title ixia_locid="61">The minimum firmware version required for Fortville NICs is NVM version
                5.04</title>
            <p ixia_locid="62">Please upgrade the firmware before installing or upgrading to this
                software release. Contact the hardware vendor for more details on the upgrade
                procedure.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N1004E_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="63">
            <title ixia_locid="64">Swift Containers and Objects are not saved as part of Backup</title>
            <p ixia_locid="65"> Contact Wind River for a manual procedure to re-create swift stores post restore.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N1005B_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="66">
            <title ixia_locid="67">The auto recovery property in the image metadata is
                ignored</title>
            <p ixia_locid="68">To turn auto recovery off for instances booting from volume, set the
                auto recovery property in the flavor instead. </p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10053_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="21">
            <title ixia_locid="22">VMs reported as ACTIVE before compute nodes are recovered</title>
            <p ixia_locid="36">During a system recovery (for example, after a site power outage),
                when the controller is available but before the compute nodes are available, the
                Nova service shows an <nameliteral ixia_locid="37">Active</nameliteral> status for VMs . Until the
                compute nodes are available, this should be an <nameliteral ixia_locid="38">Error</nameliteral>
                status.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10081_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="39">
            <title ixia_locid="40">Mismatch of interface settings in LAG group</title>
            <p ixia_locid="41">If the interfaces in a LAG group have mismatched speed or duplex settings, they are
                marked as incompatible by the system. To prevent this, ensure both interfaces in a
                LAG group use the same speed and duplex settings.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N1008E_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="42">
            <title ixia_locid="43">A node must be re-installed after MAC address change on
                management interface</title>
            <p ixia_locid="44"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="53">US82332 updated
                    interface names</draft-comment>Any change to the management interface
                configuration that results in a change of MAC address requires the node to be
                re-installed. The management interface MAC address can change if the physical
                Ethernet port is changed (for example, from enpos8 to enpos9), or if a LAG
                configuration is changed in a way that removes the Ethernet port associated with the
                LAG MAC address (for example, if the interface originally used for PXE boot is
                removed or replaced).</p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10071_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="45">
            <title ixia_locid="46">Neutron security groups are not stateful for ICMP
                protocol</title>
            <p ixia_locid="47">If a security group does not explicitly allow ingress for ICMP, then
                incoming responses to outgoing packets using ICMP are blocked. This is in contrast
                to the OpenStack implementation, where response packets are allowed regardless of
                ingress rules. </p>
        </section>
        <section id="section_N10071_N10024_N10001x" ixia_locid="48">
            <title ixia_locid="49">Hypervisor CPU usage is reported using special notation </title>
            <p ixia_locid="50">Partial vcpu notation (y.x) is adopted to show shared and dedicated vpcu model usage
                on the same compute node.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept-wr>