<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="mcu1468609327678" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="174">PCI SR-IOV Ethernet Interface Devices</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="175">A SR-IOV Ethernet interface is a physical PCI Ethernet NIC that implements
  hardware-based virtualization mechanisms to expose multiple virtual network interfaces that can be
  used by one or more virtual machines simultaneously.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="176">Edward Knowlton</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="5">The PCI-SIG Single Root I/O Virtualization and Sharing (SR-IOV) specification
   defines a standardized mechanism to create individual virtual Ethernet devices from a single
   physical Ethernet interface. For each exposed virtual Ethernet device, formally referred to as a
    <term ixia_locid="116">Virtual Function</term> (VF), the SR-IOV interface provides separate
   management memory space, work queues, interrupts resources, and DMA streams, while utilizing
   common resources behind the host interface. Each VF therefore has direct access to the hardware
   and can be considered to be an independent Ethernet interface.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="118">When compared with a PCI Passthtrough Ethernet interface, a SR-IOV Ethernet
   interface:</p>
  <ul id="ul_tyq_ymg_rr">
   <li ixia_locid="120">
    <p ixia_locid="122">Provides benefits similar to those of a PCI Passthtrough Ethernet interface,
     including lower latency packet processing.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="124">
    <p ixia_locid="126">Scales up more easily in a virtualized environment by providing multiple VFs
     that can be attached to multiple virtual machine interfaces.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="128">
    <p ixia_locid="130">Shares the same limitations, including the lack of support for LAG, QoS,
     ACL, and live migration.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="30">
    <p ixia_locid="132">Has the same requirements regarding the VLAN configuration of the access
     switches.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="134">
    <p ixia_locid="29">Provides a similar configuration workflow when used on Titanium Server.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="136">It is suggested that you read <xref href="psa1413402160578.xml" ixia_locid="138"/> first. Most configuration steps are similar, with the difference that you use
    <nameliteral ixia_locid="140">pci-sriov</nameliteral> instead of <nameliteral ixia_locid="141">pci-passthrough</nameliteral> when defining the network type of an interface.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="168"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="173">US64378 "interface" was
    "device"</draft-comment>To review the current PCI passthrough and SR-IOV interface assignments
    for a given provider network, see <ph ixia_locid="177" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="178">Titanium Server System Administration: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="179"><ph ixia_locid="180"><xref href="jow1439301559036.xml" ixia_locid="181"/></ph></cite>.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="142">In the following example a new virtual machine is launched by user
    <nameliteral ixia_locid="17">user1</nameliteral> on tenant <nameliteral ixia_locid="18">tenant1</nameliteral>, with a VF interface connected to the tenant network <nameliteral ixia_locid="19">tenant1-net1</nameliteral> identified with VLAN ID 20.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>