<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="mnh1464027762153" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Secure HTTPS External Connectivity</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Titanium Server provides support for secure HTTPS external connections
  for REST API access and Web server access.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Edward Knowlton</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <draft-comment author="eknowlto" ixia_locid="4">US78771 </draft-comment>
  <section id="section_N1009D_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="29">
   <title ixia_locid="30">Enabling HTTPS Access (optional)</title>
   <draft-comment author="eknowlto" ixia_locid="90">CGTS-4255</draft-comment>
   <p ixia_locid="91">To enable secure HTTPS access for REST API applications and the Web server, a
    digital certificate is required during software installation. When secure HTTPS connectivity is
    chosen, HTTP is disabled.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="92">For evaluation purposes, you have the option to select a self-signed
    certificate included with Titanium Server. For actual deployment, Wind River strongly recommends
    that you use a CA-signed certificate. You must obtain the certificate and copy it to the
    controller host before starting the controller configuration script. You can update the
    certificate at any time after installation.</p>
   <note id="note_N10046_N1002A_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="93">
    <p ixia_locid="94"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="95">CGTS-5418</draft-comment>If the self-signed certificate is in
     use, remote clients must be configured to accept the certificate without verifying it
     ("insecure" mode) in order to connect.</p>
   </note>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N100AD_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="48">
   <title ixia_locid="49">Installing a digital certificate</title>
   <p ixia_locid="33">To install a CA-signed digital certificate, follow the procedure for
    installing and configuring the Titanium Server system. During this procedure, you must copy the
    certificate PEM file to the controller host before running the controller configuration
    script.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N100C0_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="53">
   <title ixia_locid="55">Updating a digital certificate</title>
   <p ixia_locid="37">After you have installed a digital certificate, whether CA-signed or
    self-signed, you can update it by copying the new certificate to the active controller host, and
    then running the <cmdname ixia_locid="39">https-certificate-install</cmdname> utility as shown
    in the following example.</p>
   <codeblock ixia_locid="41"><systemoutput ixia_locid="43">$ </systemoutput><userinput ixia_locid="45">sudo /usr/sbin/https-certificate-install <varname ixia_locid="47">pem_file</varname></userinput></codeblock>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>