<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="ngo1462909796856" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Overview of Remote CLI SDK Module</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The Titanium Server remote CLI software package provides a set of CLI
  commands that can be installed on a remote workstation and used to manage Titanium Server
  remotely.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="48">Jim Owens</author>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Edward Knowlton</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <draft-comment author="eknowlto" ixia_locid="32">US76645: Remote CLI SDK Module</draft-comment>
  <p ixia_locid="34">This package is delivered in Titanium Server’s <nameliteral ixia_locid="41">wrs-remote-clients</nameliteral> SDK Module and is installable on any Ubuntu or CentOS host.
   The host must have network connectivity to the OAM IP address of the Titanium Server system in
   order to execute remote CLI commands against that Titanium Server system. The Titanium Server
   remote CLI module supports both an admin role user and a non-admin role user. It also provides
   support for both HTTP and HTTPS access, and Keystone authentication. This enables access to the
   Titanium Server CLI without requiring the user to have SSH login access to Titanium Server
   controllers.</p>
  <note id="note_N1003D_N10028_N10001" ixia_locid="61">
   <p ixia_locid="62"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="63">CGTS-5418 discuss insecure
     access</draft-comment>For HTTPS access, if Titanium Server uses the self-signed digital
    certificate included for demonstration purposes, then CLI commands from the remote client must
    be used in insecure mode (typically by including an <option ixia_locid="64">--insecure</option>
    option) to accept the certificate without verifying it.</p>
  </note>
  <p ixia_locid="5">CLI clients supported by Titanium Server’s remote CLI access include: </p>
  <ul id="ul_lkh_jzl_zv">
   <li ixia_locid="6">
    <p ixia_locid="7">Nova</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="8">
    <p ixia_locid="9">Neutron</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="10">
    <p ixia_locid="11">Cinder</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="12">
    <p ixia_locid="13">Glance</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="14">
    <p ixia_locid="15">Keystone</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="16">
    <p ixia_locid="17">Ceilometer</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="18">
    <p ixia_locid="19">Heat</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="20">
    <p ixia_locid="21">System</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="22">
    <p ixia_locid="23">OpenStack (the new OpenStack all-in-one CLI Client)</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="35">The remote CLI module does not support the Titanium Server patching CLI Client. </p>
  <p ixia_locid="40">In addition to being able to send CLI commands to a Titanium Server OpenStack
   system or region, the Remote Titanium Server CLI Client can also be used to send CLI commands to
   open-source OpenStack and/or non-Titanium Server OpenStack systems or regions. </p>
  <note id="note_N100A1_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="42">
   <p ixia_locid="43">The Titanium Server remote CLI client and the open-source OpenStack remote CLI
    client cannot be installed on the same host; only one CLI client or the other can be installed
    on a host. </p>
  </note>
  <section id="section_N10073_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="24">
   <title ixia_locid="25">Authentication</title>
   <p ixia_locid="26">All CLI commands within the Titanium Server remote CLI client are
    authenticated through Keystone. Authentication can be specified using the CLI, or retrieved from
    a shell environment. For convenience, you can download an RC file from the Titanium Server web
    administration interface and use it to export authentication parameters into the Linux shell.
    For more information, see <xref href="ahp1463003106115.xml" ixia_locid="53"/>.</p>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>