<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="nuc1473788478754" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Restrictions for Systems Using SDN</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The use of software-defined networking for Layer 3 adds some restrictions
  for Titanium Server host and network configurations. </shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="54"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="5">US84057 new
   topic</draft-comment>You can optionally enable Layer 3 management when you configure an SDN
   controller. On systems where Layer 3 management is enabled, some restrictions apply.</p>
  <section id="section_N1002E_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="55">
   <title ixia_locid="56">Restrictions for Provider Network Configuration</title>
   <ul id="ul_ldr_mz4_hx">
    <li ixia_locid="57">
     <p ixia_locid="58">Provider networks used to implement the external tenant network must be of type
       <nameliteral ixia_locid="59">flat</nameliteral>.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="60">
     <p ixia_locid="61">Provider networks used to implement internal tenant networks must be of type
       <nameliteral ixia_locid="62">vxlan</nameliteral>.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="64">
     <p ixia_locid="65">Only IPv4 backed VxLAN networks are supported. The system must not be
      configured with IPv6 addressing when SDN networking is enabled.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="66">
     <p ixia_locid="67">Additional VxLAN attributes such as TTL, multicast group-address, and
      port-number are ignored when SDN networking is enabled.</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N10029_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="6">
   <title ixia_locid="52">Restrictions for Host Configuration</title>
   <ul id="ul_sdq_km1_hx">
    <li ixia_locid="53">
     <p ixia_locid="9">Each compute host must be configured with exactly one interface with a
      network type of data-external.</p>
     <p ixia_locid="10">The data-external interface can be configured against an Ethernet, AE or VLAN interface.</p>
     <p ixia_locid="11">The data-external interface must be configured with a flat provider network.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="12">
     <p ixia_locid="13"> Interfaces with a network type of data can only be assigned a single IP address for the
      purpose of VxLAN termination.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="14">
     <p ixia_locid="15">The data and data-external interfaces cannot be combined with any other
      interface network type.</p>
    </li>
   </ul>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N10067_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="20">
   <title ixia_locid="21">Restrictions for Network Configuration</title>
   <ul id="ul_sjj_bn1_hx">
    <li ixia_locid="22">
     <p ixia_locid="23">DVR routers are not supported. This capability is inherent in the SDN layer 3 distributed
      deployment model.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="24">
     <p ixia_locid="25">The metadata service is not accessible using the metadata HTTP proxy. To obtain metadata,
      guests must be launched with the config-drive option. </p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="28">
     <p ixia_locid="29">VLAN transparent networks are not supported.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="30">
     <p ixia_locid="31">IPv6 is not supported.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="32">
     <p ixia_locid="33">For north-south routing, VMs must use floating IP addresses</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="34">
     <p ixia_locid="35">For north-south routing, SNAT is not supported</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="36">
     <p ixia_locid="37">Physical devices attached to a tenant network are accessible only if they
      are managed by OpenStack or the SDN controller.</p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="38">
     <p ixia_locid="39">The following Titanium Server network extensions are not supported, since
      they are not recognized by the OpenDaylight SDN controller:</p>
     <ul id="ul_v3m_kn1_hx">
      <li ixia_locid="40">
       <p ixia_locid="41">QoS network policies</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="42">
       <p ixia_locid="43">DNAT</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="44">
       <p ixia_locid="45">Guest VLAN subnets</p>
      </li>
      <li ixia_locid="46">
       <p ixia_locid="47">CPU scaling (due to a dependency on the metadata service)</p>
      </li>
     </ul>
    </li>
   </ul>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>