<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="qoo1462900506294" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="347">The Life Cycle of a Host</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="348">The life cycle of a host is the set of state transitions the host goes
  through as its current state changes.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="349">Jim Owens</author>
  <author ixia_locid="350">Pedro Sanchez</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="351">The host states in Titanium Server are based on the <cite ixia_locid="352">ITU
    X.731 State Management Function Specification for Open Systems</cite>. </p>
  <p ixia_locid="353">The current state of a host is determined by the allowed combinations of the
   administrative, operational, and availability states at any given time. The following figure
   illustrates the life cycle of a host.</p>
  <fig id="fig_N1029C_N10290_N10024_N10001" ixia_locid="154">
   <title ixia_locid="155">The Life Cycle of a Host</title>
   <image href="jow1404333788253.image" id="image_szm_1lq_n4" ixia_locid="156" placement="inline"/>
  </fig>
  <p ixia_locid="157">In this figure:</p>
  <ul id="ul_opf_4lq_n4">
   <li ixia_locid="158">
    <p ixia_locid="159">The administrative states, locked and unlocked, are presented in two
     columns.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="160">
    <p ixia_locid="161">The operational states, disabled and enabled, are presented in two rows.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="162">
    <p ixia_locid="163">The availability states are presented as elements inside the
     administrative/operational matrix.</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <p ixia_locid="164">The description that follows uses the availability states only, because for
   each state the corresponding administrative and operational states can be read directly from the
   figure.</p>
  <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="354">I'm not sure about the use of italics for the states. I'm not
   correcting it now but I think nameliteral might be better.</draft-comment>
  <p ixia_locid="165">The life cycle of a new host starts when it is discovered by the active
   controller on the internal management network. A new host is initially reported as
   <i ixia_locid="355">Offline</i>. As an exception, the first controller, <nameliteral ixia_locid="167">controller-0</nameliteral>, is automatically set to <i ixia_locid="356">Available</i> during initial
   commissioning. The following are the available transitions; numbers are attached to them for
   easier reference:</p>
  <dl>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="169">
    <dt ixia_locid="170">(1) <i ixia_locid="357">Offline</i> to <i ixia_locid="358">Online</i></dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="173">
     <p ixia_locid="174">This transition takes place once the administrator configures the host name
      and personality of the host. During the transition, the Titanium Server software is installed
      and the host reboots. The transition concludes when the controller establishes maintenance and
      inventory connectivity with the new host.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="175">
    <dt ixia_locid="176">(2) <i ixia_locid="177">Online</i> to <i ixia_locid="178">InTest</i>
    </dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="179">
     <p ixia_locid="180">This transition takes place when the administrator requests to move the
      host from the locked to the unlocked administrative states. The host reboots first. After it
      finishes booting, it establishes maintenance communication and enters the transient
       <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="359">Why is it tagged nameliteral here when you have been using
       italics?</draft-comment><nameliteral ixia_locid="181">InTest</nameliteral> state. While in
      this state, the configuration is applied, and a set of hardware and software tests are
      executed to ensure the integrity of the host.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="182">
    <dt ixia_locid="183">(3) <i ixia_locid="184">InTest</i> to <i ixia_locid="185">Available</i>, <i ixia_locid="186">Degraded</i>, or <i ixia_locid="187">Failed</i>
    </dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="188">
     <p ixia_locid="189">The transition is initiated automatically after the activities in the
      transient state <nameliteral ixia_locid="190">inTest</nameliteral> are complete. Depending on
      the outcome, the host goes into one the three states.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="191">
    <dt ixia_locid="192">(4) <i ixia_locid="193">Failed</i> to <i ixia_locid="194">InTest</i>
    </dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="195">
     <p ixia_locid="196">This is a value-added maintenance transition that the <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="360">high availability (HA)???</draft-comment>HA framework executes automatically
      to recover failed hosts.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="197">
    <dt ixia_locid="198">(5) <i ixia_locid="199">Available</i> to/from <i ixia_locid="200">Degraded</i>, <i ixia_locid="346">Available</i> to <i ixia_locid="202">Failed</i>, and <i ixia_locid="203">Degraded</i> to <i ixia_locid="204">Failed</i>
    </dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="205">
     <p ixia_locid="206">These are transitions that can occur at any time due to changes on the
      operational state and faults on unlocked hosts.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="207">
    <dt ixia_locid="208">(6) <i ixia_locid="209">Available</i>, <i ixia_locid="210">Degraded</i>, or
      <i ixia_locid="211">Failed</i>, to <i ixia_locid="212">Offline</i>
    </dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="213">
     <p ixia_locid="214">These are maintenance transitions that take place automatically to reflect
      the operational state of a host.</p>
     <p ixia_locid="215">On a compute node in <i ixia_locid="216">Available</i> or <i ixia_locid="217">Degraded</i> state, the transition triggers the migration of the active
      instances to another available compute node.</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>