<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE task-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River General Task//EN" "task-wr.dtd">
<task-wr id="rst1441912501217" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History
        
-->
    <title ixia_locid="327">Isolating an Untrusted Guest</title>
    <shortdesc ixia_locid="328">You can isolate the network resources used and accessible by a
        potentially untrusted virtual machine instance. </shortdesc>
    <prolog>
        <author ixia_locid="329">Ron Stone</author>
    </prolog>
    <taskbody>
        <context id="context_N1001F_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="330">
            <p ixia_locid="342"><draft-comment author="rstone" ixia_locid="341">Topic added for:
                    US60525</draft-comment>This ensures that the untrusted virtual machine cannot
                exhaust or corrupt shared network resources and impact the operation or performance
                of other virtual machines hosted on the same compute node. Note that network
                resource isolation comes at a slight degradation of network performance for this
                guest. </p>
            <p ixia_locid="339">Set this option to true when you want to isolate the network
                resources used and accessible by an untrusted guest instance from all other
                instances running on the host. Set it to false to turn isolation off. If this extra
                spec is not set, then the instance's NICs use of network resources are not isolated.  </p>
            <p ixia_locid="17">To add this extra spec to a flavor using the web administration
                interface, use the <uicontrol ixia_locid="314">NIC Isolation</uicontrol> selection
                in the <uicontrol ixia_locid="316">Create Flavor Extra Spec</uicontrol> drop-down
                menu. To access this menu, see <xref href="jow1429538642910.xml" ixia_locid="318"/>.
                This enables isolation of a virtual machine instance's NICs’ use of network
                resources from all other physical or virtual interfaces on the host. If this extra
                spec is not set, then the instance's network interfaces are not isolated. </p>
        </context>
        <prereq id="prereq_N10031_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="338">
            <p ixia_locid="340">To use this feature, the compute host must have sufficient 2 MB huge
                pages available for isolated NIC creation. For example, a guest with 3 NICs would
                require that 48 MB of 2 MB huge pages be available on its host. Isolated guests will
                only be launched on hosts that meet this requirement. For more information on using
                huge pages, see <ph ixia_locid="343" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="344">Titanium Server System Administration: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="345"><ph ixia_locid="346"><xref href="jow1423087781001.xml" ixia_locid="347"/></ph></cite>.</p>
        </prereq>
        <steps>
            <step id="step_N1003F_N1003C_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="332">
                <cmd ixia_locid="333">Set this option using the CLI:</cmd>
                <stepxmp ixia_locid="334">
                    <codeblock ixia_locid="335"><systemoutput ixia_locid="326">~(keystone_admin)$ </systemoutput><userinput ixia_locid="336">nova flavor-key flavorName set hw:wrs:nic_isolation=true</userinput></codeblock>
                </stepxmp>
            </step>
        </steps>
    </taskbody>
</task-wr>