<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="sbx1462213949416" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Titanium Server Documentation</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The Titanium Server documentation has been organized to help you locate
  information for specific types of activities, such as installation, administration, and VNF
  integration.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Edward Knowlton</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="73">Consider using a definition list &lt;dl&gt; for the following. It
   might eliminate some of the table whitespace and I don't think it is much harder to
   scan.</draft-comment>
  <table colsep="1" frame="all" id="table_lmc_ytr_zw" rowsep="1">
   <title ixia_locid="4">Titanium Server Documentation</title>
   <tgroup cols="2">
    <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
    <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1.0*"/>
    <thead>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="5">
       <p ixia_locid="6">Document</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="7">
       <p ixia_locid="8">Description</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="9">
       <p ixia_locid="10">Wind River Introduction to Titanium Server</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="11">
       <p ixia_locid="12">This document gives an introduction to Titanium Server and provides an
        overview of system capabilities, information on planning, and recommended workflows.
        Planning also helps ensure that the requirements of your hosted applications can be met, and
        the requirements of your Cloud administration and operations team can be met. It also
        ensures proper integration of Titanium Server into the target Data Center or Telecom Office,
        and helps you plan up front for future cloud growth. </p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <!-- row>
      <entry ixia_locid="13">
       <p ixia_locid="14">Wind River Titanium Server Sample Installation and Configuration</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="15">
       <p ixia_locid="16">This provides an introductory installation and configuration procedure intended to help
        familiarize you with the planning and steps required for installing Titanium Server.</p>
      </entry>
     </row -->
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="17">
       <p ixia_locid="18">Wind River Titanium Server Planning</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="19">
       <p ixia_locid="20">This helps you plan out your Titanium Server installation, ensuring that you are fully
        prepared once you start your installation and configuration. </p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="21">
       <p ixia_locid="22">Wind River Titanium Server Installation for CPE Systems</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="23">
       <p ixia_locid="24">This document provides information and instructions for installing Titanium Server
        CPE.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="25">
       <p ixia_locid="26">Wind River Titanium Server Installation for Systems with Controller
        Storage</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="27">
       <p ixia_locid="28">This document provides information and instructions for installing
        Titanium Server configurations that are initially deployed using LVM-backed block storage on
        controller nodes.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="29">
       <p ixia_locid="30">Wind River Titanium Server Installation for Systems with Dedicated
        Storage</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="31">
       <p ixia_locid="32">This document provides information and instructions for installing
        Titanium Server configurations that that are initially deployed using  Ceph-backed block
        storage on dedicated storage nodes.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="33">
       <p ixia_locid="34">Wind River Titanium Server System Administration</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="35">
       <p ixia_locid="36">This provides information pertaining to ongoing administration of a Titanium Server
        system, including information for managing the physical nodes and physical networks.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="37">
       <p ixia_locid="38">Wind River Titanium Server Software Management</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="39">
       <p ixia_locid="40">This document provides instructions for applying patches and software
        upgrades to Titanium Server hosts.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="41">
       <p ixia_locid="42">Wind River Titanium Server Cloud Administration</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="43">
       <p ixia_locid="44">This guide provides information on topics that an OpenStack administrator
        would be responsible for, except for the management of the physical nodes and physical
        networks, which is covered in the System Administration guide.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="45">
       <p ixia_locid="46">Wind River Titanium Server Tenant User's Guide</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="47">
       <p ixia_locid="48">This provides information about the operational actions that a tenant user can take. </p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="49">
       <p ixia_locid="50">Wind River Titanium Server VNF Integration</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="51">
       <p ixia_locid="52">This guide provides information to help you integrate your VNFs into a Titanium Server
        system.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <!-- row>
      <entry ixia_locid="53">
       <p ixia_locid="54">Wind River Titanium Server Troubleshooting Guide</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="55">
       <p ixia_locid="56">This provides some guidance for troubleshooting potential issues that may arise during
        installation, configuration, or use of a Titanium Server system. </p>
      </entry>
     </row -->
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="57">
       <p ixia_locid="58">Wind River Titanium Server for Regions</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="59">
       <p ixia_locid="60">This provides installation and configuration information for deploying
        Titanium Server in any of the supported Regions configurations. </p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="61">
       <p ixia_locid="62">Wind River Titanium Server Software Development Kit</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="63">
       <p ixia_locid="64">The Titanium Server Software Development Kit (SDK) provides drivers,
        daemons, API libraries,and configuration files that you can include in a guest image to
        leverage the extended capabilities of Titanium Server.These components can be used to
        enhance or extend the networking features of the applications and to access the virtual
        machine (VM) management capabilities of Titanium Server.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="74">
       <p ixia_locid="75">Wind River Titanium Server System Engineering Guidelines</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="76">
       <p ixia_locid="77">This document provides engineering guidelines, rules, and system
        parameters to assist cloud architects, installers, and administrators in planning, deploying
        and scaling the Titanium Server system.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="78">
       <p ixia_locid="79">Wind River Titanium Server Software Defined Networking</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="80">
       <p ixia_locid="81">This document provides information for using an SDN controller to manage
        Neutron services in Titanium Server.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry ixia_locid="69">
       <p ixia_locid="70">Wind River Titanium Server Release Notes</p>
      </entry>
      <entry ixia_locid="71">
       <p ixia_locid="72">These include high level details of new features in the current release,
        as well as information about known anomalies or usage caveats.</p>
      </entry>
     </row>
    </tbody>
   </tgroup>
  </table>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>