<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="tok1466082304353" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">About Tenants (Projects) and Users</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Tenants and users are system resources managed by the OpenStack Keystone
  service.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Edward Knowlton</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <section id="section_N101EC_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="112">
   <p ixia_locid="114"/>
   <p ixia_locid="116">Tenants are the core resource structure on which all end user services are
    managed. They are isolated resource containers consisting of networks, storage volumes, images,
    virtual machines, authentication keys, and users.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="117">When Titanium Server is deployed, two default tenants are created:
     <nameliteral ixia_locid="118">admin</nameliteral> and <nameliteral ixia_locid="119">services</nameliteral>. They are used to group resources to be associated with the
     <nameliteral ixia_locid="120">admin</nameliteral> user and the cloud services,
    respectively.</p>
   <note id="note_N10211_N101ED_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="121">
    <p ixia_locid="122">Earlier versions of OpenStack used the term <term ixia_locid="138">project</term> instead of <term ixia_locid="139">tenant</term>. Because of this legacy
     terminology, the Web administration interface uses both terms, and some command-line tools use
      <nameliteral ixia_locid="125">--project_id</nameliteral> when a tenant ID is expected.</p>
   </note>
   <p ixia_locid="126">Users are system resources that can operate on one or more tenants, within
    the constraints of a particular role. For each user, the Keystone service maintains a list of
    (tenant, role) tuples, which are used to determine the tenants the user can operate on, and the
    role the user should play on each of them.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="127">In the default installation of Titanium Server, several users are already
    defined. Each of the OpenStack services, such as Nova and Neutron, exist as system users. They
    all operate on the default tenant <nameliteral ixia_locid="128">services</nameliteral>.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="129">The Keystone <nameliteral ixia_locid="130">admin</nameliteral> user is
    associated with the <nameliteral ixia_locid="131">admin</nameliteral> tenant. This user has
    administrator privileges for creating, modifying, and deleting OpenStack resources, including
    creating other tenants and users.</p>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>