<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="ufp1466181495172" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Ceph-backed VM Storage</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">Titanium Server provides a flexible and scalable range of options for
    Ceph-backed storage.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
    <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="17">US74975 add remote ephemeral storage; US85034
      Swift / US84106 updates.</draft-comment>
    <p ixia_locid="18">Systems configured for Ceph-backed storage use dedicated storage hosts to
      provide storage resources for VMs. You can use these resources for VM swap, ephemeral, and
      boot-from-image root disks (remote ephemeral storage) to support persistence for live
      migration, cold migration, and evacuation. You can optionally enable additional Ceph resources
      to support Openstack object storage (Swift) access through the Ceph Object Gateway, so that
      Swift objects are accessible to VMs for use during operation.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="9"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="11">US77470 support up to four
        storage replication groups</draft-comment>Titanium Server supports up to four pairs of
      storage hosts for scalability. Allocations for ephemeral, image, object, and volume storage
      are rebalanced dynamically to meet changing requirements.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="19"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="20">US84106 mention cache
        tiering</draft-comment>Systems configured for Ceph-backed dedicated storage can use cache
      tiering to improve performance for frequently-accessed data. For more information, see <ph ixia_locid="21" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="22">Titanium Server System
          Administration: </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="23"><ph ixia_locid="24"><xref href="siv1474312502430.xml" ixia_locid="25"/></ph></cite>.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="13"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="14">US78833 / US77367 add Ceph
        storage to LVM system</draft-comment>Systems configured for controller-based storage can be
      extended to use Ceph storage. For more information, see <ph ixia_locid="26" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="27">Titanium Server System Administration:
        </cite></ph><cite ixia_locid="28"><ph ixia_locid="29"><xref href="cny1464872771057.xml" ixia_locid="30"/></ph></cite>.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>