<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="vgl1464709841372" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="386">Controller Storage</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="387">The active controller provides storage for the Titanium Server system,
  and if the system is configured for LVM-backed controller storage, for VM images and persistent
  volumes.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="388">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="389"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="390">US74975 created concept topic
    to support task topics for Horizon and CLI; added Ceph Mon Storage</draft-comment>Controller
   hosts provide the following types of storage:</p>
  <dl>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="224">
    <dt ixia_locid="225">Database storage</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="226">
     <p ixia_locid="108">the storage allotment for the OpenStack database</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="227">
    <dt ixia_locid="228">Image storage</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="229">
     <p ixia_locid="112">for a system that provides LVM-backed controller storage for VMs, the size
      of the partition to use for image storage</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="230">
    <dt ixia_locid="231">Backup storage</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="232">
     <p ixia_locid="116">the storage allotment for backup operations</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="376">
    <dt ixia_locid="377">Volume storage</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="378">
     <p ixia_locid="379"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="380">CGTS-3736 The GUI says
       "Cinder storage" but the config script says "Volume storage"</draft-comment>for a system that
      provides LVM-backed controller storage for VMs, the storage allotment for all Cinder volumes
      used by guest instances; also called <term ixia_locid="402">Cinder storage</term></p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="391">
    <dt ixia_locid="392">Image Conversion Space</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="393">
     <p ixia_locid="394"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="395">CGTS-3736
              added</draft-comment>the storage allotment for image caching and temporary image
            conversion</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="396">
    <dt ixia_locid="397">Ceph Mon Storage</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="398">
     <p ixia_locid="399"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="400">US74975
              added</draft-comment>for a system using Ceph storage, the storage allotment on the
            controller for Ceph monitoring</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
  <note id="note_N10096_N10022_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="210">
   <p ixia_locid="119">For clusters using a Ceph backend, volume storage and image storage are
        allotted on storage nodes, not on the controller node. To change the Cinder volume storage
        for a Ceph backend, see <xref href="jow1414074138348.xml" ixia_locid="239"/>.</p>
  </note>
  <p ixia_locid="25">The storage allotments are configured initially during software installation.
   You can change them using the Web administration interface or the CLI. For more information, see
    <xref href="ers1464645579505.xml" ixia_locid="401"/>).</p>
  <p ixia_locid="247">To accommodate changes, there must be enough disk space on the controller,
   including headroom needed to complete the operation. The headroom required is 45 GiB on the
   primary disk for a cluster using controller storage with an LVM backend, or 65 GiB for a cluster
   using dedicated storage with a Ceph backend. This is in addition to the space required for any
   new allotments. The requested changes are checked against available space on the affected disks;
   if there is not enough, the changes are disallowed.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="403">To provide more space, you can replace the affected disk or disks. Database,
   image, and backup storage use space on the primary disk. Cinder volume storage (on a cluster with
   an LVM backend) uses space on a disk selected by device node number during controller
   configuration. The replacement disk must occupy the same device node number. Changes to the
   Cinder volume storage can also affect the primary disk because of the headroom requirement. </p>
  <p ixia_locid="404"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="405">US78833 / US77367 mention that
    ceph mon storage can use a secondary disk</draft-comment>Ceph monitor storage uses the primary
   disk by default. If a Ceph backend is added to an existing system, and there is insufficient
   space on the primary disk for the requested Ceph monitor storage, you can specify a secondary
   disk. Note that this requires a controller re-installation.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="304"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="346">US64033 removed caution that
    controller configurations must be identical</draft-comment>To pass the disk-space checks, any
   replacement disks must be installed before the allotments are changed.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>