<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="vyn1478616249040" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Ceph Journaling and Cache Tiering</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2"/>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Craig Griffin</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <section id="section_N1001E_N1001B_N10001" ixia_locid="4">
   <title ixia_locid="5">Journal Functions</title>
   <p ixia_locid="6">Each OSD on a storage node has an associated Ceph transaction journal that tracks changes to
    be committed to disk for data storage and replication, and if required, for data recovery. By
    default, it is collocated on the OSD, which typically uses slower but less expensive hard disk
    drive-backed storage. For faster commits and improved reliability, the journals can be assigned
    to a dedicated SSD on the storage node. Wind River strongly recommends configuring the journal
    function on a dedicated SSD if hard disks are used as OSDs. If SSDs are used, the journal can be
    collocated with the OSD with no performance impact.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N1002B_N1001B_N10001" ixia_locid="7">
   <title ixia_locid="8">Cache Tiering</title>
   <p ixia_locid="9">Ceph cache tiering uses dedicated Ceph-caching storage hosts equipped with more expensive SSDs
    that provide high-speed Ceph-caching storage using SSDs in front of a set of Ceph-backing
    storage hosts using slower hard disk drive-based storage. Data is migrated to the cache tier
    when it is needed, maintained there for read-write operations, and removed when it is no longer
    required. Modified objects are removed to the storage tier (flushed), and unmodified objects are
    discarded (evicted). These operations are managed automatically by the Ceph objecter, which
    determines which tier to use for an object, and the cache tiering agent, which handles data
    migration between the tiers.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="10">Cache tiering is beneficial to performance for systems where the same few data
    objects are accessed frequently and can have a detrimental performance for some workloads,
    especially those that access a large number of objects. Cache tiering must also be configured
    with a sufficiently large cache tier to avoid cache thrashing. Wind River recommends configuring
    cache tiering only if the storage workload is known to benefit from cache tiering; otherwise
    performance may be degraded.</p>
   <note id="note_N1003B_N1002B_N1001B_N10001" ixia_locid="11">
    <p ixia_locid="12">To ensure that cache tiering is appropriate for the requirements, review the public Ceph
     documentation for caveats surrounding the use of this feature at <xref format="html" href="http://docs.ceph.com/docs/master/rados/operations/cache-tiering/?highlight=tier#aword-of-caution" ixia_locid="13" scope="external">http://docs.ceph.com/docs/master/rados/operations/cache-tiering/?highlight=tier#aword-of-caution</xref>.</p>
   </note>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>