<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="wib1463582694200" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="53">The Internal Management Network</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="54">The internal management network must be implemented as a single,
  dedicated, Layer 2 broadcast domain for the exclusive use of each Titanium Server cluster. Sharing
  of this network by more than one Titanium Server cluster is only supported in a Multi-Region
  Configuration.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="55">Jim Owens</author>
  <author ixia_locid="56">Pedro Sanchez</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="7">During the Titanium Server software installation process, several network
   services such as BOOTP, DHCP, and PXE, are expected to run over the internal management network.
   These services are used to bring up the different hosts to an operational state. Therefore, it is
   mandatory that this network be operational and available in advance, to ensure a successful
   installation.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="34">On each host, the internal management network can be implemented using a 1 Gb
   or 10 Gb Ethernet port. In either case, requirements for this port are:</p>
  <ul id="ul_uh1_pqs_hp">
   <li ixia_locid="35">
    <p ixia_locid="36">it must be capable of PXE-booting</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="37">
    <p ixia_locid="38">it can be used by the motherboard as a primary boot device</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
  <note id="note_N1005F_N1002D_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="50">
   <p ixia_locid="51"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="52">US61937 added</draft-comment>If
    required, the internal management network can be configured as a VLAN-tagged network. In this
    case, a separate IPv4 PXE boot network must be implemented as the untagged network on the same
    physical interface. This configuration must also be used if the management network must support
    IPv6.</p>
  </note>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>