<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="wkp1467914488017" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="701">Local Volume Groups</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="702">Local volume groups are used to designate one or more physical volumes on a compute host
  as collective storage space. </shortdesc>
 <prolog>
    <author ixia_locid="722">Jim Owens</author>
  <author ixia_locid="703">Edward Knowlton</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
    <p ixia_locid="8"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="82">US68057, US69978 updated
        section. US74975 added info for remote Ceph-backed option. </draft-comment>Local volume
      groups are used to designate one or more physical volumes on a compute host as collective
      storage space. Titanium Server uses one local volume group, called <nameliteral ixia_locid="692">nova-local</nameliteral>. This provides cache and file storage for the nova
      service, as well as disk storage for use by VMs. You can use the Web administration or the CLI
      to create this mandatory local volume group, and to change the settings.</p>
    <note id="note_N10038_N10022_N1001F_N10001" ixia_locid="696">
      <p ixia_locid="697"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="698">CGTS-3558 use non-root
          disks</draft-comment>Use non-root disks exclusively for <nameliteral ixia_locid="699">nova-local</nameliteral> storage. Using a root disk to provide <nameliteral ixia_locid="700">nova-local</nameliteral> storage is not a supported configuration.</p>
    </note>
    <p ixia_locid="712">The exact storage implementation depends on the <uicontrol ixia_locid="666">Instance Backing</uicontrol> type. You can set this individually for each host to use local
        <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="723">Define LVM and CoW???</draft-comment>LVM or CoW-image
      backing, or remote Ceph backing on a system that uses storage hosts. </p>
    <p ixia_locid="713">LVM and CoW backing use an <term ixia_locid="693">instances logical
        volume</term>, or <nameliteral ixia_locid="694">Instances LV</nameliteral> on the local
      compute node to hold the nova image cache and various nova control files. For CoW image
      backing, the <nameliteral ixia_locid="695">Instances LV</nameliteral> is also used to hold
      CoW-image disk files for use as VM disk storage. For LVM backing, separate volumes are used to
      provide VM disk storage. To ensure that enough space remains for this purpose, you must limit
      the <uicontrol ixia_locid="667">Instances LV Size</uicontrol>; suggested sizes are indicated
      in the Web administration interface. For more information about the Instances LV, see <xref href="jow1443470081421.xml" ixia_locid="688"/>.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="714">Ceph backing uses a Ceph storage pool, configured from the storage-host
      resources on a Ceph system. For more information, see <xref href="jhh1464706651355.xml" ixia_locid="719"/>.</p>
    <p ixia_locid="720">Compute hosts are grouped into host aggregates based on whether they offer
      LVM, CoW, or Ceph-backed storage. The host aggregates are used for instantiation scheduling.
        <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="724">Updated the doc-level &lt;cite&gt; to correct
        guide.</draft-comment>For more information, see <ph ixia_locid="182" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="183">Titanium Server Tenant User's Guide:</cite>
      </ph><cite ixia_locid="184"><ph ixia_locid="185"><xref href="jow1426182913166.xml" ixia_locid="669"/></ph></cite>. </p>
    <p ixia_locid="721">You can control whether a VM is instantiated with LVM, CoW, or Ceph-backed
      storage by setting a flavor extra specification. For more information, see <xref href="zjx1464641246986.xml" ixia_locid="670"/>.</p>
  </conbody>
</concept-wr>