<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="wmn1475417603225" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">The Provider Network Topology View</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">The Provider Network Topology view shows provider networks and compute
  host data interface connections for the system using a color-coded graphical display. Active alarm
  information is also shown in real time. You can select individual hosts or networks to highlight
  their connections and obtain more details. </shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="41">To display this view, select <menucascade ixia_locid="42">
    <uicontrol ixia_locid="56">Admin</uicontrol>
    <uicontrol ixia_locid="43">Platform</uicontrol>
    <uicontrol ixia_locid="44">Provider Network Topology</uicontrol>
   </menucascade>.</p>
  <fig id="fig_at2_fzh_mx" ixia_locid="4">
   <image href="sqw1475425312420.image" id="image_njn_jzh_mx" ixia_locid="5">
    <alt ixia_locid="6">Titanium Server Provider Network Topology view</alt>
   </image>
  </fig>
  <section id="section_N1002F_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="7">
   <title ixia_locid="8">Selection and Navigation</title>
   <p ixia_locid="9"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="10">US75601 new Provider Network
     Topology View topic</draft-comment>The Provider Network Topology view shows all compute hosts
    and provider networks graphically in a framed topology window, and lists them by name in the
     <uicontrol ixia_locid="11">Compute Hosts</uicontrol> and <uicontrol ixia_locid="12">Provider
     Networks</uicontrol> lists to the left of the window. You can select an entity using the window
    or the lists. The selected entity is highlighted in both places.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="13">If the topology of the system is too large to fit in the window, you can drag inside the
    window to see other areas.  You can also bring an entity into view by selecting it from the
    lists. The view is panned automatically to show the entity.</p>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N1004E_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="14">
   <title ixia_locid="15">Additional Details for Entities</title>
   <p ixia_locid="16">When you select an entity, associated entities are highlighted in the <uicontrol ixia_locid="17">Compute
     Hosts</uicontrol> list or the <uicontrol ixia_locid="18">Provider Networks</uicontrol> list. For example, if
    you select the <nameliteral ixia_locid="19">group0-data0</nameliteral> provider network, all hosts attached to
    it are highlighted in the <uicontrol ixia_locid="20">Compute Hosts</uicontrol> list.</p>
   <p ixia_locid="21">Additional information for the selected entity is available in tabbed pages
    below the topology window. </p>
   <ul id="ul_z5z_czh_mx">
    <li ixia_locid="22">
     <p ixia_locid="23">For a compute host, the additional information includes the <uicontrol ixia_locid="48">Overview</uicontrol>, <uicontrol ixia_locid="49">Interfaces</uicontrol>, and
       <uicontrol ixia_locid="50">LLDP</uicontrol> tabs from the <wintitle ixia_locid="55">Host Inventory
       Detail</wintitle>, as well as a <uicontrol ixia_locid="51">Related Alarms</uicontrol> tab
      that lists any active alarms associated with the host. </p>
    </li>
    <li ixia_locid="28">
     <p ixia_locid="29">For a provider network, the additional information includes the
       <uicontrol ixia_locid="52">Provider Network Detail</uicontrol> tab from the Provider Network Overview, and a
       <uicontrol ixia_locid="53">Related Alarms</uicontrol> tab that lists any active alarms associated with the
      provider network. </p>
    </li>
   </ul>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N1009C_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="32">
   <title ixia_locid="33">Alarm Reporting</title>
   <p ixia_locid="34">Active alarms for entities are displayed in real time in the topology window,
    using icons superimposed on the entities. The alarms are color-coded for severity using the same
    colors as the Global Alarm Banner. Details for the alarms are listed in the <uicontrol ixia_locid="54">Related
     Alarms</uicontrol> tab for the entity. </p>
   <fig id="fig_jmb_cvp_mx" ixia_locid="45">
    <image href="eal1475518780745.image" id="image_ydk_xvp_mx" ixia_locid="46">
     <alt ixia_locid="47">TiS Provider Network Topology alarm icons</alt>
    </image>
   </fig>
  </section>
  <section id="section_N100AD_N1001C_N10001" ixia_locid="36">
   <title ixia_locid="37">Labels for Network Connections</title>
   <p ixia_locid="38">Network connections in the topology window may be labeled with the data
    interface name (displayed above the connection line) and LLDP neighbor information (displayed
    below the connection line). You can show or hide the labels using a button above the lists
     (<uicontrol ixia_locid="39">Show Labels</uicontrol> or <uicontrol ixia_locid="40">Hide
     Labels</uicontrol>).</p>
  </section>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>