<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="xpb1466798497176" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="1">Centralized Log Collection and Analysis</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="2">You can configure Titanium Server to send detailed system logs from all
  hosts to a remote log server for centralized review and analysis.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="3">Jim Owens</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
  <p ixia_locid="31">You can also set up your own dashboards for viewing log details.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="7"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="8">US77159 / US83068 new
    topic</draft-comment>When centralized logging is enabled, logs written to the <filepath ixia_locid="9">/var/log</filepath> directory on each host are also sent to a remote log server.
   System logs used for troubleshooting and advanced analysis are included, along with the customer
   logs normally accessed from the CLI or web administration interface. By centralizing the logs,
   advanced users can apply powerful searches and advanced visualizations to examine the behavior of
   the system.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="10"><draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="30">US80148 mention TLS
    option</draft-comment> Each host sends logs through the Active Controller to a remote log server
   over the OAM network using either TCP or UDP. For added security, you can optionally configure a
   TLS connection. At the log server, an ELK (Elasticsearch, Kibana, Logstash) stack collects and
   presents the information.</p>
  <dl>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="11">
    <dt ixia_locid="12">Logstash</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="13">
     <p ixia_locid="14">collects the logs</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="15">
    <dt ixia_locid="16">Elasticsearch</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="17">
     <p ixia_locid="18"> provides a search engine</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
   <dlentry ixia_locid="19">
    <dt ixia_locid="20">Kibana</dt>
    <dd ixia_locid="21">
     <p ixia_locid="22">provides web-based visualization</p>
    </dd>
   </dlentry>
  </dl>
  <p ixia_locid="23">The ELK stack is a widely-used source log analytics engine, with ample
   documentation and tutorials on the Internet. The Titanium Server SDK includes custom searches and
   filters for use with a Titanium Server system.</p>
  <p ixia_locid="24">To set up and use a log server, see <ph ixia_locid="26" otherprops="printonly"><cite ixia_locid="27">Titanium Server System Administration:</cite>
   </ph>
   <cite ixia_locid="28"><ph ixia_locid="29"><xref href="jmz1468001809611.xml" ixia_locid="25"/></ph></cite>.</p>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>