<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept-wr PUBLIC "-//WindRiver.com//DTD DITA 1.2 Wind River Concept//EN" "concept-wr.dtd">
<concept-wr id="yey1467820597654" xml:lang="en-us">
<!-- Modification History

 -->
 <title ixia_locid="428">Improved VM Execution Environment</title>
 <shortdesc ixia_locid="429">Titanium Server provides an improved execution environment for better and more
  predictable virtual machine performance.</shortdesc>
 <prolog>
  <author ixia_locid="430">Jim Owens</author>
  <author ixia_locid="431">Pedro Sanchez</author>
 </prolog>
 <conbody>
    <draft-comment author="jmaran" ixia_locid="438">This execution environment is "improved"
      compared to what? A previous release? Other similar available commercial products? [jowens:]
      All the topics in the chapter describe improvements over native OpenStack. </draft-comment>
  <p ixia_locid="427"> Enhancements to the execution environment include:</p>
  <ul id="ul_rx5_gfs_nn">
   <li ixia_locid="432">
    <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="433">US78238 bullet added; CGTS-5780 70% memory was
          80%</draft-comment>
    <p ixia_locid="434">Platform resource utilization monitoring, to ensure that VMs can be
          scheduled on a host only if the host OS is using no more than 80% of the CPU or 70% of the
          memory allotted for platform use.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="92">
    <p ixia_locid="93">Low-latency, bounded delivery of virtual interrupts, and availability of
     low-latency high resolution timers. This is done by leveraging the optimized kernel and
     KVM/QEMU implementations of the Wind River Open Virtualization Platform (OVP).</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="94">
    <p ixia_locid="95">Option to allocate 2 MB or 1 GB huge memory pages to reduce swapping and TLB
     lookup misses.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="96">
    <p ixia_locid="97">Improved resource tracking of VMs that use dedicated CPUs, to ensure
     successful migration and evacuation.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="99">
    <p ixia_locid="100">Support for affining guest NUMA nodes to specific host NUMA nodes.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="204">
    <p ixia_locid="205">Capability to specify specific CPU models to be used by a virtual machine in
     order to leverage advanced features of the CPU architecture.</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="406">
    <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="407">US64378 added</draft-comment>
    <p ixia_locid="408">Support for PCI passthrough and SR-IOV access to Ethernet interfaces</p>
   </li>
   <li ixia_locid="413">
    <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="414">US64378 added</draft-comment>
    <p ixia_locid="415">Support for SR-IOV access to PCI-based encryption acceleration</p>
   </li>
      <li ixia_locid="435">
        <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="436">US79271 added</draft-comment>
        <p ixia_locid="437">Improved performance for standard virtio NICs using vhost-user, with
          optional multi-queue support for virtio interfaces</p>
      </li>
   <li ixia_locid="439">
    <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="440">US68056 added</draft-comment>
    <p ixia_locid="441">Option to use cached RAW images for accelerated Cinder volume creation</p>
   </li>
      <li ixia_locid="442">
        <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="443">CGTS-4963 added</draft-comment>
        <p ixia_locid="444">Option to use thin provisioning on all controller-based LVM Cinder
          volumes for faster deletion and secure deletion support, or thick provisioning for faster
          volume creation and faster initial disk writes</p>
      </li>
   <li ixia_locid="419">
    <draft-comment author="jowens" ixia_locid="420">US69978 added</draft-comment>
    <p ixia_locid="421">Copy-on-write (CoW) image-based local ephemeral storage backing for instance
     launch and delete optimization</p>
   </li>
  </ul>
 </conbody>
</concept-wr>